经典放映室
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     暴走小罐头  RiverSide152  伊森泽生
校对     暴走小罐头  RiverSide152  伊森泽生
时间轴     紫夏  无关风粤  岁半  coco
后期     8T
友情支持   @少年影视派
总监     RiverSide152  暴走小罐头
芝加哥
妈妈生病了
Mummy got sick.
病魔来得猝不及防
And it happened just like that.
大家都无能为力
There's nothing anybody could do.
这不公平
It isn't fair.
没有任何理由
There's no reason.
但如果我们开始追根究底
And if we start asking why,
我们就会走火入魔
we'll go crazy.
在微波炉里热五分钟
Five minutes in the microwave.
随便哪盒  热五分钟  就可以吃了
Any one of them. Five minutes, and done, ready to eat.
你知道怎么榨果汁吗
Do you know how to make juice?
微波炉  热五分钟
Microwave. Five minutes.
给
Here.
这是我的心理医生  联系他吧
It's my shrink. Call him.
丧偶互助小组
Loss of Spouse Support Group.
芝加哥癌症家庭网
Chicago Cancer Family Network.
失去配偶的父母  失去父母的配偶
Parents without Partners. Partners without Parents.
"拥抱自己"  "拥抱朋友"
"Hug Yourself," "Hug a Friend",
"拥抱心理医生"  或者工作
"Hug a Shrink", or work.
努力工作吧  工作会拯救你
Work hard, work will save you.
只有工作能陪你渡过难关
Work is the only thing that will see you through this.
不必介怀  他只是个失去妻子的男人
Don't mind him, he's just a guy who's lost his wife.
我想我们真正需要的是  改变
What I think we really need is change.
好主意  休几周的假
Good idea. Take a couple of weeks off,
晒晒太阳  带乔纳去钓钓鱼
get some sun, take Jonah fishing.
不  我说的是真正的改变
No, real change.
一座新城市
A new city.
一个能让我每次走过街角
Some place where every time I go around a corner
不会想起玛姬的地方
I don't think of Maggie.
瑞格利球场
芝加哥小熊队主场
你要去哪里
Where are you gonna go?
我想去西雅图
I was thinking about Seattle.
最终  几个月之后
Eventually, in a few months,
你会开始和其他女人约会
you'll start seeing women.
你会遇到某个人
You'll meet someone.
没错  向前看  没错  我就该这么做
Right, right. Move on, right, that's what I'm gonna do.
然后几个月之后
And then in a few months,
我一下子就没事了
boom, I'll be fine.
我就会长出一颗新的心
I'll just grow a new heart.
-萨姆  对不起...  -她不是那个意思
- Sam, I'm sorry... - She didn't mean that.
我知道  但我不可能再遇见真爱了
I know, I know. Look, it just doesn't happen twice.
♪你必须记住  一吻仍为一吻♪
♪ You must remember this, a kiss is still a kiss ♪
♪一叹仅为一叹♪
♪ A sigh is just a sigh ♪
西雅图夜未眠
♪纵然光阴流转♪
♪ The fundamental things apply ♪
♪有些事永远不变♪
♪ As time goes by ♪
♪当有情人尚未成眷属♪
♪ And when two lovers woo ♪
♪他们仍要甜言蜜语♪
♪ They still say "I love you" ♪
♪你可信赖于此♪
♪ On that you can rely ♪
♪无论未来如何♪
♪ No matter what the future brings ♪
♪任凭光阴流转♪
♪ As time goes by ♪
♪月光和情歌♪
♪ Moonlight and love songs ♪
♪永不过时♪
♪ Never out of date ♪
♪那些充满热情♪
♪ Hearts full of passion ♪
♪嫉妒与恨的心♪
♪ Jealousy and hate ♪
♪女大当嫁男♪
♪ Woman needs man ♪
♪男人得有伴♪
♪ And man must have his mate ♪
♪这点不可否认♪
♪ That no one can deny ♪
♪仍是同样的老旧故事♪
♪ It's still the same old story ♪
♪为了爱和荣耀而拼搏♪
♪ A fight for love and glory ♪
♪不成功  便成仁♪
♪ A case of do or die ♪
♪世界永远欢迎情人♪
♪ The world will always welcome lovers ♪
♪任凭光阴流转♪
♪ As time goes by ♪
巴尔的摩
18个月之后
那个红发的高个子姑娘是你的表妹艾琳
The tall one with red hair is your cousin Irene.
从她失望的表情你就能认出她来
You'll recognise her by the disappointed look on her face.
她嫁给了哈罗德  而他跟秘书跑了
Who was married to Harold, who ran off with the secretary.
他又回来了
Who came back
因为艾琳威胁他  如果他不回来就把狗安乐死
because Irene threatened to put the dog to sleep if he didn't.
你哥哥丹尼斯是约翰·霍普金斯大学的教授
Your brother Dennis is professor at Johns Hopkins.
他娶了  贝琪
He's married to, Betsy.
全世界最好胜的女人
The most competitive woman in the world.
我实在没办法把这些全都记住
I don't see how I'm gonna remember all this.
沃尔特  你会记住的
Oh, well, Walter, you will!
你叔叔米尔顿损失了所有的钱
Your Uncle Milton lost all of his money.
还有其他人的钱
And some other people's.
因为一场金字塔骗局
In a pyramid scheme.
所以不要提及国税局或联邦监狱系统
Don't mention the IRS or the federal prisons system.
你妈叫芭芭拉  你爸叫克里夫
Your mother's Barbara, your father's Cliff
-我爸有电动火车  -是吗
- My father has electric trains. - Really?
我会是他们的理想女婿吗
Am I what they had in mind?
沃尔特  他们会爱死你的
Oh, Walter, they're gonna love you!
各位  安妮有事要宣布
Everybody, Annie has an announcement.
沃尔特和我订婚了
Walter and I are engaged.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
妈妈事先知道  爸爸  妈妈知道的
Mum knew. Dad, Mum knew.
我没看见戒指  安妮
I don't see a ring, Annie.
祝贺你  沃尔特
Congratulations, Walter.
老天保佑  老天保佑
Bless you. Bless you!
西方习俗
在有人打喷嚏时要说bless you
-天呐  -你没事吧
- Oh, my god. - Are you all right?
没事  没事
It's nothing. It's nothing.
可能是花粉过敏吧
Maybe it's the flowers.
-我来拿走  -我们把花拿走
- I'll get them . - We'll move them.
不  别碰
No, don't touch!
我很过意不去  在这种时候打喷嚏
I feel terrible, sneezing at a time like this.
这可是我人生中的重要时刻
This is a very important moment for me.
他对什么都过敏  不用担心
He's allergic to everything, don't worry about him.
蜜蜂  我对蜜蜂过敏
Bees. I'm allergic to bees.
哈罗德对所有品种的蜜蜂都过敏
Harold is allergic to every type of bee.
我们走到哪都得带上一针肾上腺素
We always have to carry a hypodermic of adrenalin wherever we go.
只要他吃一点点坚果...
If he eats even one tiny piece of a nut...
我的头就会肿得跟西瓜一样  然后我就会暴毙
My head swells up like a watermelon and I drop dead.
哈罗德碰上蜜蜂也这样
It's the same with Harold and bees.
你妈妈和我的婚宴上有三文鱼
Your mother and I had salmon at our wedding.
婚礼上没有三文鱼冷盘那可真是...
I really think a wedding without cold salmon is...
我对三文鱼不过敏
I'm not allergic to salmon.
-他对三文鱼不过敏  -我觉得应该不过敏
- Oh, he's not allergic to salmon. - I don't think.
不过谁知道呢
But you never know.
-真的很难说  -哈罗德也不总是对蜜蜂过敏
- You never know. - Harold wasn't always allergic to bees.
亲爱的  真可惜
Oh, honey, what a shame.
我们还喝了香槟  当时是为了庆祝什么
We had some champagne. What did we use it for?
米尔顿叔叔的假释
Uncle Milton's parole.
-真的很好喝  -确实  不是吗  米尔顿
- And it was delicious. - It was, wasn't it, Milton?
你们什么时候完婚  安妮
When are you getting married, Annie?
六月初吧  在花园里办
In early June, in the garden.
-那哈罗德和蜜蜂怎么办  -我对蜜蜂过敏
- What about Harold and bees? - I'm allergic to bees.
我们会给你喷喷雾的
We'll spray you.
三文鱼冷盘  美味的黄瓜沙拉  草莓
Cold salmon, a lovely cucumber salad, strawberries.
恐怕我确实对草莓过敏
I'm afraid I am allergic to strawberries.
你能接受这个安排吗  沃尔特
Is this all right with you, Walter?
今天  我认为自己是
Today, I'm consider myself
地地地球表面面面
the luckiest man-man-man
最幸运的人人人
on the face-face-face of the earth-earth-earth.
那是电影里卢·格里克的台词
The Lou Gehrig line from...
美国著名棒球运动员  罹患渐冻症
记得吗  爸爸  这是那部电影里卢·格里克的台词
Remember, Dad, the Lou Gehrig line from...
-《扬基的骄傲》  -《扬基的骄傲》
- Pride of the Yankees. - Pride of the Yankees.
《扬基的骄傲》为卢·格里克的传记片
-《扬基的骄傲》  -没错
- Pride of the Yankees! - Yeah. Yeah.
棒球  是关于棒球的玩笑  历史典故
Baseball. It's baseball. Historical reference.
我想请大家举杯
I would like to propose a toast.
-来吧  来吧  -来吧  来吧
- Hear, hear. - Hear, hear.
敬我的妹妹
To my kid sister.
敬沃尔特和我的宝贝女儿
To Walter and my baby.
敬沃尔特和安妮
To Walter and Annie.
各位快吃吧  免得饭菜凉了
Everyone, please eat before it gets cold.
找到了
Here it is.
历史协会一直想要这个
The Historical Society wanted this
我才不会给他们
and I never would give it to them.
妈妈...
Oh, Mum...
我注意到现在流行复古风
I noticed these things are back in fashion.
外婆的婚纱
Grandmother's dress.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
他是个不错的小伙子  安妮
He's a lovely man, Annie.
我也觉得  他很棒  不是吗
I know, he is wonderful, isn't he?
-他还是个很出色的运动员  -他家人待你好吗
- And he's such a wonderful athlete. - Are his folks nice?
你会喜欢他们的
You'll love them.
我们今晚要去华盛顿跟他们共度圣诞清晨
We're going down to DC tonight to be with them Christmas morning.
-你们是怎么认识的  -其实挺傻的
- How did it happen? - Well, it's silly, really.
我在办公室见过他
I mean, I'd seen him at the office.
我当然见过他  他是副出版人
Obviously I'd seen him. He's the associate publisher.
然后有一天  我们都点了同一家店的三明治
And then one day we both ordered sandwiches from the same place
他拿了我的生菜番茄全麦三明治
and he got my lettuce and tomato on whole wheat,
当然  他对麸皮过敏
which, of course, he was allergic to.
我拿了他的生菜番茄白面包三明治
And I got his lettuce and tomato on white.
-真不可思议  -是啊
- How amazing. - It is, isn't it?
你做了无数个无意义的决定
You make a million decisions that mean nothing
然后有天你点了份外卖  却因此改变了命运
and then one day you order takeout that changes your life.
命中注定啊
Destiny takes a hand.
妈妈  命运只是我们编来自欺欺人的东西
Mum, destiny is something we've invented
因为我们无法忍受
because we can't stand the fact
凡事皆为偶然的事实
that everything that happens is accidental.
那你要怎么解释
Then how do you explain
你们俩点了一模一样的口味
that you both ordered exactly the same sandwich
只有面包不同的三明治
except for the bread?
这世界上有多少人
How many people in this world
喜欢只放生菜和番茄的三明治
like lettuce and tomato
而不是再加点别的东西  比如金枪鱼呢
without something else, like tuna?
这也算不上命运的预兆  不过是巧合罢了
Well, it wasn't a sign. It was a coincidence.
我当时和我的家人在大西洋城  克里夫是服务员
I was in Atlantic City with my family, Cliff was a waiter.
他那晚本来不该上班的
He wasn't even supposed to work that night.
想想看他要真没来会怎样呢
Suppose he hadn't?
他邀请我去钢铁码头午夜漫步
He asked me to take a midnight walk on the Steel Pier.
这故事我大概跟你说了很多遍了吧  但我不在乎
I probably told you this a million times, but I don't care.
然后他牵了我的手
Then he held my hand.
有那么一刻我向下望去
At one point I looked down
我都分不清哪根是他的手指  哪根是我的
and I couldn't tell which fingers were his and which were mine.
我当时就知道
And I knew.
知道什么
What?
你知道的
You know.
知道什么
What?
魔法  那是魔法
Magic. It was magic.
魔法
Magic.
我知道我们会永远在一起
I knew we'd be together forever.
我知道一切都会无比美妙
And that everything would be wonderful.
正如你对沃尔特的感觉
Just the way you feel about Walter.
沃尔特  这名字真正式  不是吗
Walter. It's quite a formal name, isn't it?
我确切知道的事情之一
One of the things I truly knew
就是你爸爸和我
was that your father and I were going to
会很"性"福  你们是这么说的吧
have a wonderful time in the sack, I believe you call it.
妈
Mum.
不过确实要花上几年
Of course it took several years before everything
那方面才会和谐
worked like clockwork in that department.
所以如果暂时默契不够  不必担心
So don't be worried if it takes a while.
-我们已经...  -好吧好吧  你们怎么样
- We already... - Fine, fine. Fiddly-dee. How's it working?
很和谐了
Like clockwork.
亲爱的...
Oh, honey...
-这是个预兆  -你不相信预兆的
- It's a sign. - You don't believe in signs.
他们很喜欢你  我说了他们会喜欢你的
They loved you. I told you they would love you,
果不其然吧
and they loved you.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你  沃尔特
I love you, Walter.
每个人都叫你沃尔特吗  没有别的昵称吗
Did anyone ever call you anything other than Walter?
没有
No.
你小时候也没有小名吗
Not even when you were young?
没有  小时候也没有
No, not even when I was young.
你确定我们俩要各自开车吗
You sure you don't want to drive with me?
不然我周五怎么赶回巴尔的摩
Oh, how will I get back to Baltimore on Friday?
我把礼物忘了  沃尔特
I forgot the present. Walter,
我不小心把给你继母准备的礼物忘在里面了
I left your stepmother's present inside by accident.
我发誓  等我老了  头发白了
I swear, when we're old and grey
你得提醒我把假牙戴上
you gonna have to remind me to put my teeth in.
否则我会瘪着嘴满城跑
I'll be walking all over town smacking my gums together,
丝毫没注意自己没戴假牙
not even noticing.
我等你
I'll wait.
你要等我吗  对了
You'll wait? Oh, right.
不  不必等我  沃尔特
No, don't wait, Walter.
真的  这太蠢了  你先走吧
Really, it's silly, you go ahead.
反正我们也迟到了
We're late anyway.
我大概就比你晚到十分钟
I'll be ten minutes behind you.
♪雪橇铃叮叮叮叮叮♪
♪ Sleigh bells jingle-ing Ring ting tingle-ing too ♪
♪马儿跑  马儿跑♪
♪ Horses, horses ♪
♪这是和你一起坐雪橇的好天气♪
♪ It's lovely weather for a sleigh ride together with you ♪
♪驾  驾♪
♪ Giddy-up, giddy-up ♪
华盛顿方向
♪雪花飘落  朋友欢呼♪
♪ The snow is falling and friends are calling "Yoo Hoo" ♪
♪马儿跑  马儿跑  马儿跑  铃儿响♪
♪ Horses, horses, horses, Ding ling ling♪
♪朋友欢呼  铃儿响♪
♪ Friends are calling "Yoo Hoo" Ding-a-ling-a-ling ♪
♪这是和你一起坐雪橇的好天气♪
♪ It's lovely weather for a sleigh ride together with you ♪
♪马儿跑  马儿跑♪
♪ Horses, horses ♪
♪叮叮当  叮叮当  铃儿响叮当♪
♪ Jingle bells, jingle bells Jingle all the way ♪
♪今晚滑雪多快乐  我们坐在雪橇上♪
♪ Oh, what fun, it is to ride in a one horse open sleigh, hey ♪
♪叮叮当♪
♪ Jingle bells ♪
♪马儿跑  马儿跑♪
♪ Horse, horses ♪
欢迎回到"电台心情"
Welcome back to "You and Your Emotions."
♪铃儿响叮当♪
♪ Nothing all the way ♪
我是玛夏·菲尔斯通医生
I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone,
此刻我正在芝加哥希尔斯大厦顶层
broadcasting live across America
向全美听众直播
from the top of the Sears Tower in Chicago.
今晚  我们来聊聊愿望与梦想
Tonight we're talking about wishes and dreams.
你在这个平安夜许下了什么愿望
What's your wish this Christmas Eve?
你的愿望是什么  我的愿望就是换台
What's your wish? My wish is to turn the radio station.
也许你能给自己的最好礼物就是向我致电
Maybe the best present you can give yourself is a call to me
.
芝加哥的电话是
The number in Chi--
今晚健康讲堂的主题是
Subject of this evening's medical update is:
"你和你的脾脏"
"You and your spleen."
-今晚的主讲人是...  -想都别想
- And your host is... - Not on your life.
接下来您将听到的是
Coming up,
倒放版《铃儿响叮当》
"Jingle Bells" backwards,
演唱者是新泽西的凯特·梅耶兹
sung by the New Jersey Kate Mayze.
来自西雅图的听众  说吧
Seattle, go ahead.
你好  我是乔纳...
Hello, this is Jonah...
不要把姓说出来  乔纳
No last names, Jonah.
你的声音听起来比我们一般的来电听众要年轻
You sound younger than our usual callers.
你多大了
How old are you?
我八岁了
I'm 8.
八岁吗  怎么这么晚还不睡觉
Eight? How come you're up so late?
西雅图还没那么晚
It's not that late in Seattle.
芝加哥的时间比西雅图早两小时
当然了  你说得没错
Oh, of course, you're absolutely right.
好了  你的圣诞愿望是什么  乔纳
All right, what's your Christmas wish, Jonah?
这个愿望不是为我自己许的  是为了我爸爸
It's not for me, it's for my dad.
我觉得他需要一个新妻子
I think he needs a new wife.
你不喜欢他现在的妻子吗
You don't like the one he has now?
他现在没有妻子  这就是问题所在
He doesn't have one now. That's the problem.
你妈妈呢
Where's your mum?
她去世了
She died.
-我很遗憾  -真是难以置信
- Oh, I'm so sorry to hear that. - Well, who can believe this?
我很难过  但我觉得我爸爸更伤心
I've been pretty sad, but I think my Dad's worse.
你跟你爸爸聊过这事吗
Have you talked to your dad about this?
-没有  -为什么呢
- No. - Why not?
这样好像会让他更伤心
It's like it makes him sadder.
我可以理解
I can understand that.
乔纳  你爸爸现在在家吗
Jonah, is your dad home right now?
-在的  -他在干什么  他忙吗
- Yeah. - What's he doing? Is he busy?
不忙吧  他在外面的露天平台上
Not really, he's out on the deck.
我相信我可以帮到他
I'm sure that I can help.
但我需要你的协助
But I'm gonna need you to help me to help him.
-这个坏女人  -所以我希望你做的就是
- Wretched woman! - So what I want you do
-把你爸爸带到电话前  -快挂电话  乔纳
- is bring your dad to the phone. - Hang up, Jonah!
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
不可能  他会杀了我的
No way, he'd kill me.
相信我  乔纳
Trust me, Jonah.
当他发现你有多担心他时  他不会生气的
He won't be angry when he realises how concerned you are about him.
-想赌一把吗  -好吧  但如果我被骂了
- Wanna bet? - Okay, but if I get yelled at,
我就再也没法听你的节目了
I'm never gonna listen to your show again.
好吧  有道理
Okay, fair enough.
-爸爸  -怎么了
- Dad? - Yeah.
有人打电话找你
There's someone on the phone for you.
-他叫萨姆  -萨姆
- His name is Sam. - Sam.
如果您刚开始收听  我是玛夏·菲尔斯通医生
If you've just tuned in, this is Dr. Marcia Fieldstone
今晚的主题是你的愿望和梦想
and tonight's topic is your wishes and dreams.
我来接吧
Okay, I got it.
我们现在正在和某位西雅图的听众连线
We're on the line now with someone from Seattle.
你好
Hello.
你好  萨姆  我是美国电台的菲尔斯通医生
Hello, Sam, this is Dr. Fieldstone on Network America.
好吧  今晚你要推销什么
Okay. What are you selling tonight?
微波烤肉炉还是日本银座刀
The micro-hibachis or the Ginza knives?
不  我不是来推销的  我只想帮忙
No, I'm not selling anything. I just wanna help.
我想让你知道你儿子打来了电话
I want you to know that your son called
他向我咨询如何才能让你另觅新欢
and he asked me for some advice on how you might find a new wife.
你是哪位
Who is this?
美国电台的玛夏·菲尔斯通医生
Dr. Marcia Fieldstone of Network America.
我们正在直播
And you are on the air.
你给电台打电话了
You called a radio station?
萨姆  萨姆  萨姆  你在听吗
Sam, Sam, Sam, are you with me?
在的  在听
Yeah. Yes.
你儿子觉得自从你妻子过世后
Your son feels that since your wife's death
你一直都很不开心
you've been very, very unhappy.
他真的很担心你
And he is genuinely worried about you.
过来  过来
Get out here. Get out here.
快点  我才不要一个人接这通电话
Come on, now, I'm not gonna go through this alone.
我认为对他来说  跟你谈论这件事非常艰难
I think it's very hard for him to talk to you about all this.
我想也许你和我可以谈谈
I thought maybe you and I could talk,
这会让乔纳心里更好受一些  萨姆
it would make Jonah feel a little better. Sam?
跟她谈谈吧  爸爸  她是个医生
Talk to her, Dad. She's a doctor.
哪方面的医生
Of what?
万一她名字就叫医生呢
Her first name could be Doctor.
拜托嘛
Please.
萨姆  这是他的圣诞愿望
Sam. Sam, it's his Christmas wish.
-好吧  -很好
- Okay. - Okay. Good.
我知道这不容易
Now, I know this is difficult.
不过尊夫人是多久前去世的
But how long ago did your wife die?
大概一年半前
About a year and a half ago.
从那以后你谈过恋爱吗
Have you had any relationships since?
-没有  -没有吗  为什么
- No. - No? Why not?
玛夏  还是我该叫你菲尔斯通医生
Marcia, or should I call you Dr. Fieldstone?
叫我玛夏医生好了
Dr. Marcia.
-玛夏医生  -玛夏医生  我无意冒犯
- Dr. Marcia. - Dr. Marcia. I don't mean to be rude...
我也不想侵犯你的个人隐私
And I don't want to invade your privacy...
-你明明太想了  -你明明太想了
- Sure you do. - Sure you do.
继续说吧  萨姆  我在听
Go on, Sam. I'm listening.
萨姆
Sam.
一开始的日子很煎熬
We had a pretty tough time there at first.
但我们在慢慢接受
But we're dealing with it.
乔纳和我会好好生活下去
And Jonah and I will get along just fine again,
等我砸了他的收音机就行
as soon as I break his radio.
毫无疑问  你是个好爸爸
I have no doubt that you're a wonderful father.
其实  从一个人的声音里可以听出很多东西
You know, you can tell a lot from a person's voice.
确实如此
You certainly can.
但如果乔纳仍觉得你闷闷不乐
But something must be missing
那你心里一定还残缺着什么
if Jonah still feels that you're under a cloud.
我就问你几个问题  你晚上能入睡吗
Just a few questions: Are you sleeping at night?
他完全睡不着
He doesn't sleep at all.
-你怎么知道  -我住在这里  爸爸
- How do you know that? - I live here, Dad.
圣诞节快到了
Look, it's Christmas.
玛姬  我妻子
Maggie, my wife.
她真的...
She really did it...
我是说  她很喜欢...
I mean, she loved...
她让一切都如此美好
She made everything beautiful.
因此每年的圣诞都会很难熬
It's just tough this time of year.
哪个孩子不需要妈妈呢
Every kid needs a mother.
有没有可能你和乔纳一样  都需要某人的陪伴
Could it be that you need someone just as much as Jonah does?
-是的  -不必回答
- Yes. - Don't answer that.
等听完听众反馈后我们再继续
Let's get into that right after these messages.
萨姆  乔纳  不要挂断
Sam, Jonah, don't go away.
如果您刚开始收听
If you've have just tuned in,
我们正在跟一位来自西雅图的夜未眠先生连线
we are talking to Sleepless in Seattle.
我们将倾听一些听众反馈 休息之后马上回来
And we'll be right back after this break with your listener response.
她在说什么
What is she talking about?
这时候其他人可以打电话进来
This is when other people get to call in
评论你刚刚说的话
and dump on what you said.
这还挺有意思  也挺有帮助
Well, this is really fun. And helpful.
首都餐厅
我敢说他人又高  屁股又翘
I bet he's tall with a cute butt.
我敢说他好几周都没洗澡  身上臭得要命
I bet he hasn't bathed in weeks and he stinks.
哈莉叶  闭嘴吧  您好  您要点什么
Harriet, shut up. Hi, can I help you?
给我一杯茶  不要茶包
Tea, with the bag out.
也许我该直接去西雅图
You know, maybe I'll just hustle myself up to Seattle,
送他一个除夕夜的小礼物
give him a little gift for New Year's Eve.
随你  你要去就去吧
Yeah, you go on out there if you want to.
但别打开他的冰箱
But don't open his refrigerator.
他们把东西放进冰箱时什么都不盖
They don't cover anything when they put it in the fridge
他们只是把东西放在里面  然后离开
they just stick it in there and leave it
直到东西自己走出去
till it walks out by itself.
我的意思是  就算他在我床上吃零食
All I'm saying is I wouldn't kick this guy
我也不会把他踹下去
out of my bed for eating crackers.
你懂我意思吧  65美分
You know what I'm saying? Sixty five cents.
在接回西雅图之前  让我们来接听一通电话
Let's take a call before we get back to Sleepless.
来自田纳西州诺克斯维尔的这位听众  请说吧
Knoxville, Tennessee, you are on the air. Talk to me.
好的  我只是想知道
Yes, I would just like to know
我从哪里可以得知这位先生的住址
where I could get this man's address.
亲爱的  先去排队吧
Honey, get in line.
下一位听众  请讲
Next caller, go ahead.
请允许我问一个问题...
If there was one question I was allowed to ask...
问吧
Oh, go ahead.
真正爱过的人  更有可能再次陷入爱河
People who truly loved once are far more likely to love again.
萨姆  你觉得你还能像爱你妻子一样
Sam, do you think that there is someone out there you could love
爱另一个人吗
as much as your wife?
玛夏·菲尔斯通医生  这很难想象
Well, Dr. Marcia Fieldstone, that's hard to imagine.
那你打算怎么办
What are you going to do?
我打算每天早上起床
Well, I'm going to get out of bed every morning
一整天都保持呼吸
and breathe in and out all day long.
一段时间过后  我就不必再提醒自己
And after a while I won't have to remind myself
每天早上要起床  要保持呼吸
to get out of bed every morning and breathe in and out.
再过一段时间  我就不会再想着
And then after a while I won't have to think about
我也曾拥有过一段精彩而完美的人生
how I had it great and perfect for a while.
萨姆  告诉我你的妻子究竟有何特别之处
Sam, tell me what was so special about your wife.
你的节目有多长时间
Well, how long is your programme?
其实是无数件小事
Well, it was a million tiny, little things.
当这些小事积少成多
When you added them all up,
这就意味着我们注定在一起
it just meant we were supposed to be together.
我知道
And I knew it,
当我第一次触碰她时我就知道了
I knew it the very first time I touched her.
感觉就像回家
It was like coming home,
我不曾知晓的那个家
only to no home I'd ever known.
我当时只是牵着她的手
I was just taking her hand
扶她下车
to help her out of a car.
于是我就知道了
And I knew it.
那感觉就像...
It was like...
-魔法  -魔法
- Magic. - Magic.
听众朋友们  节目是时候结束了
Well, folks, it's time to wrap it up.
我是芝加哥的玛夏·菲尔斯通医生
I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone in Chicago.
祝各位听众朋友们度过一个魔法般的美妙圣诞
And to all my listeners, a magical and merry Christmas.
至于你  这位来自西雅图的夜未眠先生
And to you, Sleepless in Seattle,
我们希望你能尽快再次来电  让我们知晓后续
we hope you'll call again soon and let us know how it's going.
♪你将在那里找到我♪
♪ It's where you find me ♪
那是一定的
Oh, you can count on it.
♪我知道在彩虹之上♪
♪ I know somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪有蓝鸟飞翔♪
♪ The blue birds fly ♪
♪蓝鸟飞翔♪
♪ Birds fly ♪
♪飞翔在彩虹之上♪
♪ Over the rainbow ♪
♪那么为何  为何我不能飞翔♪
♪ Why then, oh why can't I? ♪
巴尔的摩太阳报报社
这家伙卖的汤一定是你喝过的最好喝的
This man sells the greatest soup you've ever eaten,
却又是全美国最刻薄的人
and he is the meanest man in America.
我有强烈的预感  贝琪  不仅仅是汤
I feel very strongly about this, Becky. It's not just about soup.
写吧  还有什么素材吗
Do it. What else?
除夕  拜托别让我写这个主题
New Year's Eve. Please don't make me write it.
听听这个
Listen to this:
"大芝加哥地区的通讯于平安夜
"Phone service in the greater Chicago area was tied up
中断两小时
for two hours Christmas Eve
只因某个孩子给电台节目打电话
when some kid calls a phone in radio show
说他爸爸需要一位新妻子"
and says that his dad needs a new wife."
两千名女性打电话给电台
Two thousand women called the station
索要那位先生的电话号码
asking for the guy's number.
-天哪  -我听到了
- Jesus. - I heard it.
那孩子来电说  "我爸爸需要一位妻子"
This kid calls up and says, "My dad needs a wife."
那个心理医生几乎是逼他来接电话  然后说
And the shrink head practically forces the guy on the phone and says,
"你想聊聊这事吗"
"Do you want to talk about it? "
他说  "不  其实我不想"
And he says, "No, as a matter of fact, I don't."
然后突然间  毫无缘由地
And then suddenly for no reason at all
他就开始说他有多爱他妻子
he start to talk about how much he loved his wife
他是如何爱上了她
and how he just fell in love with her
就好像他是密歇根的那些奶牛之一
like he was one of those cows in Michigan.
什么密歇根的奶牛
What cows in Michigan?
《时事60分钟》上播过
It was on 60 Minutes
那些奶牛被杂散电压电死了
over those cows that got zapped by stray voltage.
没人知道原因  也许是在威斯康辛州吧
No one knows why. And maybe it was Wisconsin.
不过  无论如何
But, anyway,
我当时听着他说他有多爱妻子
I was listening to him talk about how much he loved his wife
忽然我就哭了
and suddenly I was crying.
我看那些电话公司的广告时也会这样
It's like what happens when I watch those phone company ads.
都不用全部看完
I don't have to see the whole thing,
只要看女儿把冰箱送给妈妈那一段
just the part where the daughter gives the mother the refrigerator
-上面还系着个红蝴蝶结  -红蝴蝶结
- with the big red bow. - ... big red bow
没错  还有宝丽来的广告
Yes. The Polaroid commercial,
两个五岁小孩在他们祖父的生日派对上
two 5-year-olds at their grandfather's birthday party.
-他们在用胶水往相册上贴照片  -太戳心了
- They're making the album with the glue. - That kills me!
你应该写写这事
You should write something about this.
写什么事
About what?
管它算什么事  写就是了
Whatever it is.
我告诉你这算什么事
I tell you what it is:
两千个女人给电台打电话就为了找老公
Two thousand women calling a radio station for a husband?
如今急不可耐要追寻爱情的女人真是一抓一大把
There are a lot of desperate women out there looking for love.
尤其在过了某个特定的年龄之后
Especially over a certain age.
你要知道  被恐怖分子杀掉的几率
You know it's easier to be killed by a terrorist
都比在四十岁之后成功结婚要高
than it is to get married over 40.
不是这样的  这个统计结果是假的
That is not true. That statistic is not true.
确实如此  不是真的  但感觉像真的
That's right, it's not true. But it feels true.
感觉像真的  因为这就是真的
It feels true because it's true.
其实还有人写了本书
There is practically a whole book
来论证这项统计结果有多假
about how that statistic is not true.
冷静点  是你挑起的话头
Calm down, you brought it up.
我才没有  怀亚特
I did not, Wyatt.
你读过那本书吗
Did you even read that book?
有谁读完过那本书吗
Did anybody read that book all the way through?
你俩吵完了吗
Are you two finished?
行  我们刚刚说到哪儿了
Fine, now where were we?
如果某人是个鳏夫
If someone's a widower,
为什么人们要说他是"寡居"
why do they say that he was "widowed"?
为什么不说他是"鳏居"呢
Why don't they say he was "widowered"?
我只是好奇罢了
I was just wondering.
刚刚是怎么回事
What was that about up there?
什么怎么回事
What was what?
你怎么了
What's with you?
我没事啊
Nothing's with me.
你肯定有事
Something's with you.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
不管什么事  你都可以告诉我
Whatever it is, you can tell me.
西雅图夜未眠先生
Sleepless in Seattle?
她在节目中就这么称呼他的  因为他晚上会失眠
That's what she called him on the show because he can't sleep.
于是现在有两千个女人想要他的电话号码
And now 2000 women want his number.
那家伙可能是个疯子
The guy could be a crackhead,
异装癖者  暴露狂  瘾君子  电锯杀人狂
a transvestite, a flasher, a junkie, a chainsaw murderer
或者是个死变态  就像我家里克
or someone really sick, someone like my Rick.
其实  他听上去像是个很好的人
Actually, he sounded nice.
是吗
Oh, really?
终于说到点子上了
Now we're getting down to it.
拜托  贝琪  我正和沃尔特热恋
Please, Becky. I'm madly in love with Walter.
那天晚上他做了一件超疯狂的事
He did the craziest thing the other night.
是什么事来着
What was that?
特别有意思  我们都笑疯了  是什么事来着
Oh, it was so funny, we were hysterical, what was that?
我在想着
You know, I was thinking,
我不是得去波士顿参加生物分析学家大会吗
I've gotta go to Boston for the AAB convention, right?
之后我还要去温斯顿·休斯公司
And then I gotta visit Winston-Hughes
谈谈更换电脑的相关事宜
about switching over our computers...
我们何不在纽约见面
Why don't we meet in New York
共度情人节周末呢
for Valentine's Day weekend.
沃尔特  我很愿意
Walter, I'd love to!
我们可以住在广场酒店
We can stay at the Plaza.
在中央公园滑冰
Ice skate in Central Park.
登记
Register.
登记吗
Register?
是啊  登记盘子  玻璃杯  银器  所有想要的礼品
Yeah, for dishes, glasses, silver, everything.
怎么样
How about it?
我要带你去唐人街吃点心
I'll take you to Chinatown for dim sum.
里面有小麦吗
Does it have wheat in it?
应该没有
I don't think so.
♪点心  点心♪
♪ Dim sum, dim sum ♪
十  九  八  七  六
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six
五  四  三  二  一
five, four, three, two, one.
乔纳  醒醒  水晶球要降落了
Hey, Jonah, wake up, wake up. The ball's dropping.
纽约时代广场新年夜传统
倒计时和跨年水晶球
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
来  我抱你
Okay, pal. I got ya.
没事
It's okay.
走喽
There we go.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
给霍华德一个晚安吻
Kiss Howard.
晚安  霍华德
Good night, Howard.
♪有时我会想♪
♪ Sometimes I wonder ♪
♪我为何♪
♪ why I spend ♪
♪用许多孤独的夜♪
♪ the lonely nights ♪
♪去想一首歌♪
♪ dreaming of a song ♪
♪那旋律♪
♪ The melody ♪
♪萦绕在我的幻想中♪
♪ haunts my reverie ♪
♪让我再次伴你身旁♪
♪ And I am once again with you ♪
♪当你我初恋♪
♪ When our love was new ♪
♪每个吻都妙不可言♪
♪ And each kiss an inspiration ♪
♪但那已是多年以前♪
♪ But that was long ago ♪
♪如今我的慰藉♪
♪ Now my consolation ♪
♪在一曲星尘之中♪
♪ is in the stardust of a song ♪
♪在花园的围墙边♪
♪ Beside a garden wall ♪
♪当星星仍闪烁♪
♪ When stars are bright ♪
♪我拥你入怀♪
♪ you are in my arms ♪
♪夜莺啼声婉转♪
♪ The nightingale ♪
♪诉说他的童话♪
♪ tells his fairytale ♪
♪关于盛开着玫瑰的天堂♪
♪ of paradise where roses grew ♪
我能喝一半你的啤酒吗
Can I have half your beer?
能啊  喝吧
Sure, go ahead.
我以前经常怎么说的来着
What did I used to say?
"这杯敬你"
"Here's looking at you"?
"干杯"
"Here's mud in your eye."
"敬我们"
"Here's to us."
你以前经常说的是  "敬我们"
You used to say, "Here's to us."
亲爱的
Oh, babe.
我想你想到心痛
I miss you so much it hurts.
-你要干什么  -等他来的时候告诉他
- What do you wanna do? - Well, tell him, tell him when he gets here.
-你想告诉他吗  我不介意  -你能告诉他吗
- You want to tell him? I don't mind telling him. - You can tell him?
-她来了 -她回来了  她有别的想法
- She's here. - She's back. She has another idea.
-别走别走  -我可没这功夫
- No, no, no. - I don't need this.
-萨姆  很高兴你来了  -你还好吗  克莱尔
- Sam, I'm so glad you're here. - Claire, how are you?
我听到你在节目里说的话了  我已经跟大家说了
I heard you on the radio. I told everyone about it.
-我们已经知道了  -你们是怎么...
- We already knew. - How did you...?
-格蕾丝  -那个调度员
- Grace. - The dispatcher?
-没错  -那全西雅图都知道了
- Yeah. - All of Seattle knows.
我当时正在刷牙  忽然我就听到了你的声音
I was brushing my teeth and, suddenly, there you were.
我不敢相信自己的耳朵
I just couldn't believe my ears.
我给我妈打了电话  她在拉斯维加斯
I called my mother in Las Vegas.
我说  "妈  打开收音机
I said, "Mother, turn on the radio.
节目里的人是我的建筑师"
That's my architect."
一个男人能吐露内心的感受真的很好
You know, it's so nice when a man can express his feelings.
-真的很棒  -没错  我也希望自己能表达内心
- It's wonderful. - Yeah, I wish I could express my feelings.
那么  克莱尔  有什么问题吗
So, Claire, is there a problem?
昨晚我辗转反侧
I was tossing and turning last night.
你知道那是什么感觉  萨姆
You know what that's like, Sam.
因为我意识到我们订的那个冰箱
Because I realise I'm never going to fit my platters
绝对装不下我那些大盘子
in that refrigerator we ordered.
当我办派对时  总是会用大盘子
And when I give parties, I always put in platters.
所以我觉得还是订零下的那个冰箱好了
So I thought I would get the sub-zero refrigerator instead.
唯一的问题就是...
And the only problem...
我们得重做所有的橱柜
We have to redo all the cabinets.
我们得...  得打进这堵墙
We're gonna... We'll be into this wall.
-那是承重墙  -克莱尔  那样就得延工...
- That's bearing wall. - That's a delay, Claire, of...
-两  三...  -五  六...
- Two, three... - Five, six...
-十二周  -我不介意
- Twelve weeks. - I don't mind.
重要的是搞定这事
The important thing is to get it right.
-保证搞定  -你说话要算话
- Absolutely. - Your words.
我得走了  室内装潢师来电话了
Oh, I've gotta rush. La décorateur calls.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
这就是命运
Well, this is fate.
她离婚了
She's divorced,
我们不想重做橱柜  而你缺个老婆
we don't wanna redo the cabinets, and you need a wife.
当这一切交织在一起时  那叫什么来着
What do they call that, when everything intersects?
百慕大三角
The Bermuda Triangle.
还有一个  你还拿得下吗
And here's another one. Do you got room for one more here?
给你  在这签名
Here you go. Right there.
看看  爸爸  这些都是寄给你的
Look at this, Dad. They're all for you.
没错  先生  拿着
Yes, sir. Here you go.
"西雅图夜未眠先生"
"Sleepless in Seattle,"
玛夏·菲尔斯通医生转交
C/o Dr. Marcia Fieldstone.
如果你睡不着  你可以试试
If you're having trouble sleeping, you might wanna try
从杯子远离嘴的那面喝水
drinking a glass of water from the other side.
-我还以为这办法是用来治打嗝的  -能治打嗝吗
- I thought that was for hiccups. - Does it work for hiccups?
要治打嗝的话  舀一勺糖
For hiccups, take a spoonful of sugar,
含在嘴里一分钟
hold it in your mouth for a minute.
真的吗
Really?
谢谢
Thank you.
你为什么把我们的地址给他们
What possessed you to give them our address?
他们打电话过来问了
They called and asked for it.
"亲爱的西雅图夜未眠先生
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle
你是我听过的最有魅力的男人"
you're the most attractive man I ever lay ears on."
等等  他们打电话来了
Wait, wait, wait. They called?
他们怎么会有我们的电话号码
How did they get our number?
让我猜猜  你告诉他们的
Oh, let me guess. You gave it to them.
你必须把电话号码给他们
You have to give them your phone number
否则就不让你上节目
or they won't let you on the air.
"亲爱的西雅图夜未眠先生  我住在塔尔萨"
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle. I live in Tulsa."
那地方在哪里
Where's that?
在俄克拉荷马州
It's in Oklahoma.
-你知道俄克拉荷马在哪吗  -中部某个地方吧
- You know where Oklahoma is? - Somewhere in the middle.
我都不愿意去想
I'm not even gonna think
学校到底有多少东西没教你
about what they're not teaching you in school.
我都不愿意去想
I'm not even gonna think about it.
没错  是在中部某个地方  总的来说
Yeah, somewhere in the middle. And, generally speaking
我们应该排除任何不住在这附近的人
I think we should rule out anyone that doesn't live near here.
她愿意飞到任何地方
She's willing to fly anywhere.
她长得像我三年级的老师
She looks like my third-grade teacher.
我讨厌我三年级的老师
I hated my third-grade teacher.
等等
Wait a minute.
她就是我三年级的老师
She is my third-grade teacher!
这些信你一封都不打算看吗
Aren't you gonna read any of these?
不打算  因为事不是这样办的
No. Cause this is not how it's done.
我更愿意
I'd much rather just
见见我喜欢的人
see somebody I like
面对面地感受她们
and get a feeling about them,
问问她们想不想出去喝一杯
ask them if they wanna have a drink.
-或者吃点披萨  -不吃晚餐
- Or a slice of pizza? - Not dinner.
初次约会不一定要共进晚餐
Not necessarily on the first date,
因为晚餐吃到一半
because halfway through dinner,
你可能会很后悔约对方共进晚餐
you could be really sorry you asked them to dinner.
不过  如果只是喝一杯的话
Whereas, if it's just a drink
如果你喜欢对方  总有机会邀请她共进晚餐
if you like them, you can always ask them to dinner.
但如果没感觉  你也可以直接说
But if not, you can just say,
"嗯  今晚挺不错的"
"Well, that was great,"
然后就各回各家
And then you go home.
懂我的意思了吗
You see what I mean?
我很好奇现在的约会方式还是不是这样
I wonder if it still works this way.
不是了  女孩子会主动邀请你
It doesn't. They ask you.
我开始注意到了
I'm starting to notice that.
如果你娶了个新老婆  你应该会跟她上床吧
If you get a new wife, I guess you'll have sex with her, huh?
我当然希望如此
I certainly hope so.
她会抓你的背吗
Will she scratch up your back?
什么
What?
电影里  女人总是抓着男人的背尖叫
In movies, women always scratch up the man's back and screaming.
他们上床时就会这样
Stuff when they are having sex.
你怎么会知道
How do you know this?
杰德家有有线电视
Jed's got cable.
杰德家有...
Oh, Jed's got...
把你身后那条毛巾递给我
Hand me that towel behind you.
-谢谢  -我也得擦擦
- Thank you. - I need it too.
来  我来帮你擦
Here, let me get you.
"杰德家有有线电视"  来吧
"Jed's got cable!" Come on.
♪又一对新婚夫妇♪
♪ Another bride, another groom ♪
♪又一个阳光灿烂的蜜月♪
♪ Another sunny honeymoon ♪
♪又一个季节  又一个理由♪
♪ Another season, another reason ♪
♪来寻欢作乐♪
♪ For makin' whoopee ♪
♪当午后艳阳高照♪
♪ When the sun is high in the afternoon sky ♪
♪你总能让自己忙碌起来♪
♪ You can always find something to do ♪
♪但从早到晚  时钟滴答♪
♪ But from dusk till dawn as the clock ticks on ♪
♪有些事悄然发生♪
♪ Something happens to you ♪
♪在凌晨时分♪
♪ In the wee small hours of the morning ♪
♪那时全世界仍在安睡♪
♪ While the whole wide world is fast asleep ♪
♪你独自清醒♪
♪ You lie awake ♪
♪想着那个男孩♪
♪ And think about the boy ♪
♪也没想过要数羊来使自己入睡♪
♪ And never ever think of counting sheep ♪
欢迎回到玛夏·菲尔斯通医生的节目精选集
Welcome back to the best of Dr. Marcia Fieldstone
她是一位临床心理学家  也是你从未有过的挚友
clinical psychologist and the friend you never had.
还记得迈阿密的孤独小姐吗
Remember Marooned in Miami?
他说他不再爱我了
He says he doesn't love me anymore.
你为什么会想和一个不爱你的人在一起
Why would you wanna be with someone who doesn't love you?
丹佛的失望女士
Disappointed in Denver.
每次我快高潮的时候
Every time I come close to orgasm,
他都会抽身去给自己做三明治吃
he goes to make himself a sandwich.
你为什么不提前给他做个三明治呢
Why don't you make him a sandwich beforehand.
西雅图的夜未眠先生
Sleepless in Seattle.
我打算每天早上起床
Well, I'm going to get out of bed every morning.
一整天都保持呼吸
Breathe in and out all day long.
一段时间过后  我就不必再提醒自己
And then after a while, I won't have to remind myself
每天早上要起床  要保持呼吸
to get out of bed every morning and breathe in and out.
再过一段时间  我就不会再想着
And then after a while, I won't have to think about
我也曾拥有过一段精彩而完美的人生
how I had it great and perfect for a while.
萨姆  告诉我你的妻子究竟有何特别之处
Sam, tell me what was so special about your wife?
你的节目有多长时间
Well, how long is your programme?
其实...
Oh, well, it was...
其实是无数件小事
Oh, it was a million tiny, little things.
当这些小事积少成多
When you added them all up
这就意味着我们注定在一起
it just meant that we were supposed to be together.
我知道
And I knew it.
当我第一次触碰她时我就知道了
I knew it the first time I touched her.
感觉就像回家
It was like coming home,
我不曾知晓的那个家
only to no home I'd ever known.
我当时只是牵着她的手
I was just taking her hand,
扶她下车
to help her out of a car.
然后我就知道了
And I knew it.
那感觉就像
It was like...
魔法
Magic.
我觉得我要疯了
Well, I think I'm going crazy,
丹尼斯  我真的快疯了  你的婚姻幸福吗
Dennis. I really do. Are you happily married?
-什么  -我是说...
- What? - I mean...
你为什么要结婚  是因为那些乐队和烟火吗
Why did you get married? Was it all trumpets and fireworks?
我结婚是因为贝琪说我们要么分手要么结婚
I got married because Betsy said we had to break up or get married.
于是我们就结婚了
So we got married.
但当你初次遇见她时
But when you first met her,
你相不相信她就是你的真命天女
did you believe that she was the only person for you,
而这一切都是命运神秘的安排
that in some mystical, cosmic way it was fated?
安妮
Annie,
当你被某人吸引  只能说在潜意识中
when you're attracted to someone, it means your subconscious
你的潜意识被他们的潜意识吸引了
is attracted to their subconscious, subconsciously.
我们所认为的命运
What we think of as fate is
不过是两个疯子觉得他们是天造地设的一对罢了
just two neuroses knowing they're a perfect match.
我甚至都不认识他
I don't even know him.
我在幻想一个我未曾谋面的男人
I'm having all of these fantasies about some man I've never even met,
他还住在西雅图
who lives in Seattle!
西雅图一年之中有九个月都在下雨
It rains nine months of the year in Seattle.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我不想搬去西雅图
I do not wanna move to Seattle.
但我真正不希望的
But what I really don't wanna do
是总幻想着可能会发生的一切
is end up always wondering what might've happened
并明知自己本可以做些什么
and knowing I could've done something.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我只是临阵退缩  不是吗
It's just cold feet, isn't it?
每个人在结婚前都会恐慌
Everybody panics before they get married.
难道你没有过吗
I mean, didn't you?
我有过
Yes, I did.
没错  你有过  多谢你了  丹尼斯
Yes, you did. Thank you very much, Dennis.
把这些话说出来之后我觉得好多了
I feel so much better just having blown this off.
随时效劳
Anytime.
桑迪有个闺蜜  格伦达  她是个举重运动员
Sandy has a girlfriend, Glenda. She's a weightlifter.
那姑娘可不是什么脑袋大脖子粗的货色...
Alright, it's not like her neck is bigger than her head...
不不不  我不是让你帮我介绍对象
No, I'm not asking you to set me up.
我不需要你帮那种忙
I don't need your help with that.
我只是想知道  现在的情场是怎样的
I wanna know what it's like, you know, out there.
我就是想告诉你这个
That's what I'm trying to tell you
女人们寻求的是什么  胸肌和翘臀
what women are looking for: Pecs and a cute butt.
-比如"他的屁股超翘"吗  -没错
- Well, you mean like, "He has the cutest butt." - Yeah.
-我最近是从哪儿听来的这话  -到处都在说
- Where did I hear that recently? - Everywhere.
这年头你开个电视
You can't even turn on the news nowadays
都免不了听见某些姑娘对男人的屁股评头论足
without hearing some babe thought some guy's butt was cute.
我不知道是哪个女人起的头
Who the first woman to say this was, I don't know,
但这话莫名其妙就火了
but somehow it caught on.
那么我的屁股如何
So how's my butt?
-还不错  -是吗
- Not bad. - Really?
-是啊  -不过算得上翘吗
- Yeah. - Is it cute though?
我不知道  是按曲线打分的吗
I don't know. Are we grading on a curve?
你上次和人约会是什么时候
When was the last time you were out there?
吉米·卡特当总统的时候  1978年
Jimmy Carter, 1978.
现在情况有些不同了
Things are a little different now.
首先  你们得做朋友
First, you have to be friends.
你们得喜欢彼此
You have to like each other.
然后你们会拥吻
Then you neck.
这个阶段可能会持续好几年
This could go on for years.
然后你们要去体检  接着你就可以戴套和她上床
Then you have tests, then you get to do it with a condom.
好消息就是大家各付各的帐
The good news is you split the cheque.
我觉得我是不会让女士付晚餐钱的
I don't think I could let a woman pay for dinner.
真棒  她们会为你举办一个游行
Great! They'll throw a parade in your honour.
你会是《西雅图杂志》上的年度男士
You'll be Man of the Year in Seattle Magazine.
提拉米苏
Tiramisu.
-什么是提拉米苏  -你会知道的
- What is tiramisu? - You'll find out.
-到底是什么  -你会明白的
- Well, what is it? - You'll see.
如果某个女人想让我对她做那个
Some woman is gonna want me to do it to her,
但我却不知道那是什么  那怎么办
and I'm not gonna know what it is.
你会喜欢的
You'll love it.
这太难了
Oh, this is gonna be tough.
太难了  太难了  重返情场比我想的要难多了
Tough, tough. It's gonna be much tougher than I thought.
你觉得本内特雇的那个装潢师怎么样
What about that decorator on the Bennett job?
-维多利亚吗  -没错  她很活泼
- Victoria? - Yeah. She's perky.
-不  我不...  -怎么了
- Oh, no, I don't... - What?
-这根本就不是我的风格  -什么  不
- That's not I'm way. I'm far away from that. - What? No.
-我目前只是在收集信息...  -信息
- I'm just assembling notes. I'm not... - Notes.
-我要怎么办  -什么叫你要怎么办
- How would I do that? - What do you mean how do you do?
你给她打电话
You call her up.
你就说  "我们见个面  看一下颜色板"
You say, "Come, let's get together. We'll look at swatches."
给她打电话
Call her on the phone
说  "来  我们看一下颜色板"
to say, "Come, let's look at swatches"?
对啊  配色方案嘛
Yeah, you know, colour schemes.
她难道不会看穿我的企图吗
She's not gonna see right through that?
不  你不必学我的招数
No, you don't do it like I do it.
你可以用你自己的那种温和方式
You do it in your own suave way.
想想加里·格兰特[著名男演员]Think Cary Grant.
-加里·格兰特会打电话说...  -想想加里·格兰特
- Cary Grant would call up and say, - Think Cary Grant.
-"过来看一下我的颜色板"吗  -拜托
- "Come over and look at my swatches"? - Hello.
你怎么知道  也许他会呢
How do you know? Maybe he did.
-他没有这么做  -我知道他没有在电影里这么做
- He didn't do it. - I know he didn't do it in the movies.
-你是说《古庙战笳声》吗  他没有...  -不是
- Gunga Din? He didn't call...? - No.
《古庙战笳声》不是那种爱情电影
Gunga Din is not a swatch kind of movie.
谁知道他在现实生活中会怎么做
Who knows what he did in real life.
但他对黛恩·坎农用了这招吗
But he did that with Dyan Cannon?
美国女演员  加里·格兰特前妻
可不是嘛
Yeah, sure.
"你好  黛恩  来看看这些颜色板吧"
"Hello, Dyan! Take a look at these swatches."
乔纳  我回来了
Jonah, I'm home!
乔纳
Hey, Jonah!
Jonah?
乔纳
Hey, Jonah.
乔纳  人呢
爸爸  这位是杰西卡
Hi, Dad. This is Jessica.
很高兴认识你  杰西卡
Well, it's nice to meet you, Jessica.
爸爸  这真的太不可思议了
Dad, this is amazing.
如果你倒着放这张碟  听上去就像"保罗死了"
If you play this backwards, it says "Paul is dead."
对  没错  我知道
Yeah, yeah. I know.
你怎么会知道
How do you know?
爸爸  你能把门关上吗
Dad, could you shut the door?
当然  当然
Sure. Sure.
你  再
H and G.
你好  再见
Hi and goodbye.
♪我又重新跨上了马鞍♪
♪ I'm back in the saddle again ♪
♪去到那个地方  那里朋友都真心实意♪
♪ Out where a friend is a friend ♪
♪那里长角牛们都吃♪
♪ Where the longhorn cattle feed ♪
♪吃那低矮的石膏草♪
♪ On the lowly gypsum weed ♪
♪我重又跨上马鞍♪
♪ Back in the saddle again ♪
♪再一次驰骋原野♪
♪ Ridin' the range once more ♪
♪带着我那把老手枪♪
♪ Totin' my old.44 ♪
♪那里你每晚露宿旷野♪
♪ Where you sleep out every night ♪
♪唯一的法则就是正确♪
♪ And the only law is right ♪
♪我重又跨上马鞍♪
♪ Back in the saddle again ♪
你好  是维多利亚吗
Hello, Victoria?
我是萨姆·鲍德温  我不知道你是否记得我  但...
This is Sam Baldwin. I don't know if you remember me, but...
太好了
Oh, great.
我在想...
I was wondering if...
你是否愿意和我喝一杯
If you would like to have a drink with me?
晚餐吗
Dinner?
晚餐那就更好了
Dinner would be even better.
周五挺好的  没问题  没问题
Friday would be great, yeah, yeah.
那要怎样...  我听说那里很不错
How...? I hear that's a good place.
7点半可以
7:30 would be fine.
那我就...
And I'll...
好的  我们在那里见面  好的  没问题
Okay, I'll meet you there. Okay. All right.
所以我们在周五晚7点半共进晚餐
So it's Friday at 7:30 for dinner.
很好
Great.
我也是  再见
Me too. Bye.
♪我重又跨上马鞍♪
♪ Back in the saddle again ♪
你爱他吗
Are you in love with him?
现在不爱
I'm not now.
那时的人们还懂得如何去爱
Now those were the days when people knew how to be in love.
-你没救了  -他们知道的
- You're a basket case. - They knew it.
时间  距离  没什么能将他们分开  因为他们知道
Time, distance, nothing could separate them because they knew.
-那是对的  那是真的  那是...  -一部电影
- It was right. It was real. It was... - A movie.
这就是你的问题所在  你想的不是谈恋爱
That's your problem. You don't wanna be in love.
你想的是在电影里谈恋爱
You wanna be in love in a movie.
把写的信读给我听听
Read it to me.
"亲爱的夜未眠先生及其子
"Dear Sleepless and Son.
我此生从未写过这样一封信..."
I've never written a letter like this in my life..."
大家在给陌生人写信的时候
That's what everyone writes
都会千篇一律用这个开头
at the beginning of letters to strangers.
我知道啊  你以为我不知道吗
I know that. You think I don't know that?
沃尔特怎么办
What about Walter?
沃尔特
Oh, Walter.
只要能嫁给沃尔特  我愿意付出一切
Oh, I'd give anything to marry Walter.
他是如此的出人意料
He's so unexpected.
你以为你能看穿他的为人
You think you can tell what he's like by just looking at him,
但你不能
but you can't.
我应该在信里写点跟魔法有关的东西
I should write something in this about magic.
什么
What?
总要写点什么吧  万一我永远不会遇见他呢
Something! What if I never meet him?
万一他是我的真命天子  而我却永远不会遇见他呢
What if this man is my destiny, and I never meet him?
真命天子也有可能是命中灾星  看看我和里克
Your destiny can be your doom. Look at me and Rick.
"我想见你..."
"I want to meet you..."
在帝国大厦楼顶见面如何
How about the top of the Empire State Building?
我想在帝国大厦楼顶见你
On the top of the Empire State Building.
在情人节的黄昏
Sunset, Valentine's Day.
我那时会和沃尔特一起待在纽约  我可以挤时间去
I'll be in New York with Walter. I can squeeze it in.
我会和沃尔特一起待在纽约
I'll be in New York with Walter!
你想听听什么叫命运弄人吗
Do you wanna hear about destiny?
如果我没有嫁给马丁
If I hadn't married Martin
我就不会买下那栋长着一棵死树的房子
I never would've bought the house with the dead tree.
也正因此我才离婚
On account of which I got divorced.
也正因此我才会撞到别的车
On account of which I hit a car
并且在买颈托的时候遇到里克
and met Rick while buying a neck brace.
等等
Wait a minute.
你从没告诉过我你离婚是因为一棵死树
You never told me you got a divorce because of a dead tree?
是因为那个绿化工
The tree man.
你爱上了一个绿化工
You fell in love with the tree man?
我没说"爱"
I did not say "Love."
我说"爱"了吗
Did I say "Love"?
这是我最喜欢的一段
This is my favourite part.
机不可失  时不再来
It's now or never.
时不再来  听着有些吓人
Never is a frightening word.
傻子才会让幸福擦肩而过
We'd be fools to let happiness pass us by.
对那些没有温暖回忆的人来说  冬天一定很冷
Winter must be cold for those with no warm memories.
我们已经错过了春天
We've already missed the spring.
是啊
Yes.
男人永远看不懂这部电影
Men never get this movie.
我也觉得
I know.
妈妈  妈妈
Mummy! Mummy!
-妈妈  -没事的  没事的
- Mummy! - It's okay. It's okay.
我在呢
I'm here.
-爸爸  -我来了
- Dad! - I'm coming.
没事了  别怕  没事了
It's all right. It's okay. It's okay.
没事的  不用怕  没事的
It's okay, it's all right. It's okay.
-做什么噩梦了  -在下沉
- What was that about, huh? - It was sinking.
-什么在下沉  -我们家
- What was? - Our house.
每个窗口都有水涌进来
There was water coming in all the windows.
现在没事了
Well, it's okay now.
没事了
It's all right.
那我们该怎么办呢
So, what should we do?
你以前做噩梦的时候  妈妈会给你唱歌
Your mother used to sing to you when you had bad dreams.
《再见黑鸟》
"Bye Bye Blackbird."
是啊
Yeah.
我想她了
I miss her.
你觉得一个人死了之后  会发生些什么
What do you think happens to someone after they die?
-我不知道  -比如  你相信有天堂吗
- I don't know. - Like, do you believe in heaven?
我从未相信过
I never did.
我也不相信会有死后的世界  但现在  我不知道了
Or the whole idea of an afterlife. But now, I don't know.
因为我会做一些梦
Because I have these dreams about...
梦到你妈妈
about your mum.
没错  我们会聊上很久
Yeah. And we have long talks.
聊聊你  你过得怎么样
About you. How you're doing.
她应该也知道  不过我还是会告诉她
Which she sort of knows, but I tell her anyway.
这是怎么回事呢
So, what is that?
她应该就在死后的世界吧  不是吗
It's sort of an afterlife, isn't it?
我开始忘记她了
I'm starting to forget her.
她可以削完一个苹果
She could peel an apple
长长卷卷的皮是完整的
in one long, curly strip.
削一整个苹果都不会断
The whole apple.
♪收起我所有的忧虑和悲伤♪
♪ Pack up all my cares and woes ♪
♪情绪依旧低落♪
♪ Feeling low ♪
♪我也应该离开♪
♪ Here I go ♪
♪我说了再见♪
♪ I said bye ♪
♪再见♪
♪ Bye ♪
我爱你  乔纳
I love you, Jonah.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
♪我要去那个有人在等我的地方♪
♪ Where somebody waits for me ♪
明天见
See you tomorrow.
♪她甜如蜜糖♪
♪ Sugar sweet so is she ♪
♪再见  我说了再见♪
♪ Bye I said bye ♪
♪再见  黑鸟♪
♪ Bye Blackbird ♪
♪似乎没有人爱我♪
♪ No one seems to love ♪
♪或理解我♪
♪ Or understand me ♪
♪还有那些倒霉故事♪
♪ And all the hard luck stories ♪
♪他们总是不断地讲给我听♪
♪ They keep handing me ♪
♪若有人愿意给我一丝光明♪
♪ Where somebody shines the light ♪
♪今夜我将回到故乡♪
♪ I'm be coming on home tonight now ♪
♪再见  再见  我想说♪
♪ Bye, bye, I wanna say ♪
♪再见黑鸟♪
♪ Blackbird ♪
♪上帝慈悲♪
♪ Lord have mercy ♪
♪关于爱情♪
♪ About loving now, yeah ♪
劳瑞
Laurie?
你好  我是安妮
Hi, it's Annie.
没事  没事  我挺好的
Fine, fine. I'm fine.
我正在写一篇关于电台热线节目的文章
Listen, I'm doing an article on call-in radio shows.
你认不认识什么人
Do you know anyone who works for someone
在一个叫玛夏·菲尔斯通医生的手下工作
named Dr. Marcia Fieldstone?
我是《巴尔的摩太阳报》的一位撰稿人
I'm a writer for the Baltimore Sun,
也是劳瑞·约翰逊的朋友
and a friend of Laurie Johnson's.
我在写一篇文章  关于人们如何承受丧亲之痛
I'm doing a piece on how people handle bereavement.
我知道前几天晚上你们有一位听众
And I understand you had a caller the other night,
是来自西雅图的一位先生
some guy from Seattle.
我是乔纳·鲍德温
This is Jonah Baldwin.
我们现在不在  但你可以...
We're not in right now, but you can...
鲍德温
Baldwin.
欢迎来到市新闻局
新闻搜索
请输入需求
查找  萨缪尔·鲍德温
查找到216个萨缪尔·鲍德温
按Y键打印或查看结果
查找萨缪尔·鲍德温  乔纳·鲍德温
查找到萨缪尔·鲍德温  乔纳·鲍德温
按Y键打印或查看结果
已故: 玛格丽特·艾伯特·鲍德温
萨缪尔之爱妻  乔纳之慈母
葬礼办于6月10日  上午10点
已故: 玛格丽特·艾伯特·鲍德温
萨缪尔之爱妻  乔纳之慈母
葬礼办于6月10日  上午10点  周四
天安教堂  纽约州110号
花束将被转送至芝加哥园艺协会
芝加哥新闻服务  1991年6月12日
查找萨缪尔·鲍德温  芝加哥
查找到萨缪尔·鲍德温
按Y键打印或查看结果
萨缪尔·鲍德温  于1961年因重大偷窃罪被逮捕
萨缪尔·鲍德温  市政委员  于1967年因贪污受贿被定罪
萨缪尔·鲍德温  建筑师  建造过城市广场
萨缪尔·鲍德温  标枪世界纪录保持者
建筑师
Architect.
萨缪尔·鲍德温  1961年因重大偷窃罪被逮捕
萨缪尔·鲍德温  市政委员  于1967年因贪污受贿被定罪
萨缪尔·鲍德温  建筑师  建造过城市广场
萨缪尔·鲍德温  标枪世界纪录保持者
传真界面
AAA侦探事务所
西雅图
西雅图  华盛顿州
背景调查  包括照片
调查对象为萨缪尔
AAA侦探事务所
西雅图  华盛顿州
背景调查  包括照片  调查对象为萨缪尔  现居西雅图
建筑师  请秘密回复
好了  克拉丽丝
Okay, Clarise.
要是一切顺利  我就午夜回来
I'm gonna be back either by midnight
如果不顺利  就明早8点半回来
or 8:30, if disaster strikes.
这封信是写给我们俩的
Here's one for the both of us.
-"致夜未眠先生及其子"  -现在我把我要去的
- "Sleepless and Son, - Now I left the number of the restaurant
-"来自巴尔的摩"  -那家餐厅的号码留给你们
- Baltimore." - where I'm gonna be at
如果出事了  儿科医生的号码
If there's any problem, here's the number to the paediatrician
就在电话旁边
and it's right about the phone.
如果有人不小心喝了毒物  这里有一瓶催吐剂
Here's a bottle of Ipecac if anybody drinks poison.
就在果汁杯旁边
It's right next to the juice glasses.
好吧
Fine.
-我看上去怎么样  -挺好的
- How do I look? How do I look? Huh? - Great.
我看上去还好吗  还行吗
Do I look okay? Do I look all right?
我看上去好蠢  感觉这样打扮用力过猛了
I look stupid. I look stupid. I look like I'm trying too hard.
本来想去剪个头发
I was gonna get a haircut,
现在我看着就像已经剪过了头发
but I'd just look like I got a haircut.
这封信写得很不错  爸爸
This is a good letter, Dad.
这双鞋的鞋跟形状很奇怪
Look, the heels on these shoes are grotesque.
感觉就像我在穿增高鞋  我为什么要这么做呢
I look like I'm trying to be tall. Why am I trying to be tall?
-她的名字叫安妮  安妮·里德  -我已经很高了
- Her name is Annie. Annie Reed. - I'm already tall.
我要迟到了  再见
Now I'm late. Bye.
爸  看一下这封信
Dad, read this.
看一下
Read this!
"致夜未眠先生及其子...
"Sleepless and Son...
在所有人的印象中
I have been an excellent third baseman
我都一直是一个很出色的三垒手
for as long as I or anyone else can remember
既然谈到了这个话题  这么说吧
and while we're on the subject, let's just say right now:
布鲁克斯·罗宾森是有史以来最出色的三垒手
Brooks Robinson was the best third baseman ever.
你能同意这个观点  对我来说很重要
It's important that you agree with me on that
因为我是巴尔的摩人"
because I'm from Baltimore."
她认为布鲁克斯·罗宾森最出色  你也这么认为
She thinks Brooks Robinson is the greatest. So do you.
-大家都这么认为  -这是个预兆
- Everyone thinks thinks Brooks Robinson is the greatest. - It's a sign.
过来
Come here.
我让你看看什么叫预兆
I'll show you a sign.
这里就有个预兆
Here's a sign.
好了
All right.
西雅图在哪
Where's Seattle?
没错  巴尔的摩在哪
Right. Where is Baltimore?
在这  你看
It's right there! Look!
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four. There's, like,
这两个地方之间隔了26个州  这才是预兆
26 states between here and there. Now, that's a sign.
我要出门了
I'm out of here.
再见
Goodbye!
晚安
Good night!
我爱你
I love you.
克拉丽丝  你把车挪开了吗
Clarise, did you move your car?
-谢谢  德里克  -不客气
- Thank you, Derrick. - You're welcome.
-我要...  -白葡萄酒
- I'll have... - White wine spritzer?
-没错  -你呢  先生
- Yes. - And you, sir?
我不用了  谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
-你很漂亮  -你也很帅
- You look good. - You look good yourself.
我还以为你永远不会给我打电话
I thought you'd never gonna call me.
-你真的这么想  -我真的很希望你打电话
- You did? - I really wanted you to.
但我以为你永远不会给我打电话
And I thought you were never going to.
-打扰一下  鲍德温先生  -怎么了
- Excuse me, Mr. Baldwin? - Yes.
有你的电话
There's a phone call for you.
失陪
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂
Hello.
爸爸  我们能去纽约过情人节吗
Dad, can we go to New York City for Valentine's Day?
什么
What?
来自巴尔的摩的安妮·里德
Annie Reed from Baltimore
想在情人节当天
wants to meet us at the top
和我们在帝国大厦楼顶见面
of the Empire State Building on Valentine's Day.
-乔纳  -怎么了
- Jonah? - What?
你跌倒了吗  在流血吗
Have you fallen down? Are you bleeding?
克拉丽丝在吗  她被勒死了吗
Is Clarise there? Has she been strangled?
-没有  -所以你打电话来就为了这个
- No. - So this is the only reason for this phone call?
如果我们现在订往返机票  可以享受优惠
If we book now, we can get an excursion fare.
杰西卡的父母是旅行代理人  杰西卡的...
Jessica's parents are travel agents, and Jessica's...
我现在不想和你谈论这个话题
I'm not having this conversation right now.
我们晚点再谈
We'll talk about it at a later time.
我不敢相信就这点破事我们居然能聊这么久
I can't believe this conversation has lasted this long.
你赶快上床睡觉
You go to bed.
-一切还好吧  -没事
- Everything all right? - Oh, yeah.
-你有孩子吗  -没有
- Do you have kids? - No.
想要我的孩子吗
Do you want mine?
我要一杯不加冰的绝对伏特加  谢谢
I'll have an Absolut straight up, please.
好
Sure.
放下  别玩了
Hey, hey! Put that down. Stop it!
她来了
There she is.
她为什么要带食材过来
Why is she bringing those groceries?
她要为我们下厨  你要做好准备
She's gonna cook us something so be prepared.
你好  萨姆  谢谢
Hi, Sam. Thanks.
谢谢
Thanks.
我猜猜
And let me guess.
你一定就是乔纳了
You must be Jonah.
你好
Hi.
-就这么多吗  -没错
- So this it? - Yeah.
-车在那边  -太好了
- The car's down this way. - Great.
这都是她换的第六个油漆工了
She's on her sixth painter
这活永远都干不完了
and we are never going to finish this job.
现在她又想把壁炉重新装一遍
Now she wants the fireplace rebricked.
我很了解她  我可以给她打个电话
I know her pretty well. I could give her a call.
不用了  我可以解决
No, I've got it solved.
我用那些壁炉砖头砸她就行了
I'll just hit her with one of those bricks.
太好笑了  你真风趣
That's so funny. You're so funny.
当她想装修的时候  她就会开始喋喋不休
When she wants something done she goes this whole song and says,
"我不知道  我好蠢
"Oh, I don't know. I'm stupid.
你告诉我吧  你比我清楚
You tell me. You know better than I would.
我们能不能直接把房子翻个面
But couldn't we flip the house around
这样的话  所有东西都会移动到另一边
so that everything on one side is now on the other,
本来在后面的东西会移动到前面
everything in the back is now in front?
能不能给房子的前门装上一个大铰链
And could the whole front of the house open on one great big hinge
这样我就能用车库开门器开门了"
that I can get in with a garage opener."
"当然  当然可以这么做  只是需要..."
"Well. Yeah. Yeah, we can. We can do that. We'll just gonna have to..."
"拆掉橱柜"
"Move the kitchen cabinets."
乔纳  你吃完之后把餐具拿过来  好吗
Hey, Jonah, bring some of that stuff around, all right?
你喜欢棒球吗
Do you like baseball?
喜欢  我公司有西雅图水手队的包厢票
Yes, I do. In fact my firm has box seats to the Mariners.
不如我们以后一起去看
Why don't we all go some time.
-那露营呢  -露营怎么了
- What about camping? - What about it?
你喜欢露营吗
Do you like camping?
我曾经露营过一次
I went camping once.
爸爸  我们以后应该经常去露营
You know what, Dad, we ought to start camping more often.
你说得对  露营很不错  上床时间到了
You're right. Camping is good. Time for bed.
-现在才10点  -没错  10点  上床时间
- It's only 10:00. - Yeah, 10:00. Time for bed.
晚安
Good night.
难道你不想感谢维多利亚为我们做了美味晚餐吗
Hey, don't you wanna thank Victoria for this delicious dinner?
谢谢你做的晚餐
Thanks for dinner.
我第一次看见有人这么做土豆
I never saw anybody cook potatoes that way.
很高兴你喜欢
I'm glad you liked it.
晚安  乔纳
Good night, Jonah.
我们家不太吃土豆  我们比较喜欢吃米饭
Yeah, we don't see a lot of potatoes around here. We're rice men.
天哪
Oh, God.
-对不起  沃尔特  -对不起
- I'm sorry, Walter. - I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-喂  -打开收音机
- Hello. - Turn on your radio.
-怎么了  -那个孩子在热线上
- What? - The kid is on.
你害得我都开始听这破节目了  去打开收音机
You've got me listening to this garbage. Go, turn it on.
谁啊
Who is it?
是贝琪  她又和里克闹矛盾了
It's Becky. She's having trouble with Rick again.
我下楼  我下楼打电话  贝琪  我等会儿回电
I'll go downstairs. I'll go downstairs, Becky. I'll call you back.
对不起  沃尔特  你流血了吗
I'm sorry, Walter. Are you bleeding?
听上去他现在正在亲她
Sounds he's kissing her right this minute!
真的吗
Oh, really?
乔纳  说实话  你在监视你父亲吗
Jonah, tell the truth. Are you spying on your father?
他现在在亲谁
Who is he kissing right this minute?
-我得阻止他们  -你觉得...
- I have to make them stop. - Do you think...
我该怎么向沃尔特解释
How will I explain this to Walter?
她过来为我们做晚饭
She came over and cooked dinner.
她带了两袋食材  就好像要过来住上一整年
She brought two bags of groceries like she was staying here for a year!
乔纳  乔纳
Jonah, Jonah,
你父亲开始约会是好事
it's good that your father's dating.
只是你难以接受罢了
It's just hard on you.
你以为自己希望父亲开始约会
It's something you think you want,
但你父亲真的开始约会之后  又吓到了你
but then when it happens, it scares you.
不是这样的
That's not true.
好了  你想想
Okay, now think.
难道你父亲不应该自己判断
Shouldn't your father be the judge
一个人到底适不适合他吗
of whether someone is right or wrong for him?
他还不够理智  什么也判断不了
He's not sane enough to judge anything.
现在他在亲她的嘴
Now he's kissing her on the lips.
她是坏女人  我爸被坏女人迷倒了
She's a ho. My dad's been captured by a ho!
我该怎么办
What am I going to do?
冷静  乔纳  冷静
Calm down, Jonah, calm down.
明天早上
Tomorrow morning,
你和爸爸吃早饭的时候
when you're sitting down to breakfast with your dad,
告诉他你的感受
tell him how you feel.
把自己的感受闷在心里不好
It's not good to keep your feelings inside you.
身穿红衣  躲在杂物柜里  还拿着收音机
Miss Scarlet. In the broom closet. With the radio.
沃尔特
Walter,
你吓到我了  以后不许这样
you scared me. Don't ever do that again.
我好像看见了一只黑寡妇蜘蛛
I thought I saw a black widow spider.
你吓死我了  你也把维多利亚吓死了
You scared me to death. You scared Victoria to death.
就在那里
It was right over there.
下一次  你以为自己
Next time you think you see
看见黑寡妇蛛的时候  我希望你说
a black widow spider I want you to say:
"爸  打扰一下
"Dad, excuse me,
我觉得家里进了一只有毒的昆虫"
but I believe a poisonous insect is in the house."
然后我会冷静地过来处理
And I will calmly come and take care of it.
你要再这么尖叫  我就宰了你
You scream like that again, I'll kill you.
贝琪在收音机上听到一个人来电  她很肯定是里克
Becky heard this guy on the radio, she was sure it was Rick.
她气坏了
She was completely hysterical.
后来才发现这个人住在德卢斯  德卢斯在哪
And then it turned out the guy lived in Duluth. Where's Duluth?
这没道理啊
That doesn't make any sense.
我知道  沃尔特  完全没道理
I know. I know, Walter. It doesn't make any sense at all.
谢天谢地  我的生活井然有序
Thank God my life is in place.
德卢斯在北达科他州
Duluth? That's in North Dakota.
我喜欢这封信  你得给她回信
I love this letter. You have to write to her.
你真的这么想吗
You think so?
-这是「你唯希」 -是吗  那是什么意思
- It's Y-O-H. - Yeah. What's that?
你唯一的希望
Your only hope.
我想为这些电台节目做报道
I thought I would look into doing a story on those radio shows.
你大概还得去别的地方好好调查一下
You'd probably have to go somewhere to really look into them.
肯定的
Definitely.
难道你不能进行电话采访吗
Couldn't you do a phone interview?
我想做的这篇报道不行
Not for the kind of piece I wanna do.
我不会在芝加哥待太久的
I won't be in Chicago that long.
等你回来  我都走了
When you get back, I'll be gone.
那我们就纽约见
Then I'll see you in New York.
我来开门
I'll get it.
我是布朗宁机长  目前的飞行高度为10668米
This is Captain Browning. We're cruising at 35,000 feet.
西边的天气晴朗
The weather looks clear to the west
预计可以按时到达西雅图
and we expect to arrive in Seattle on schedule.
-你讨厌乘飞机吗  -讨厌
- Don't you hate flying? - Yes, I do.
Flying (乘飞机)和 Lying (撒谎)
发音有点相似
我刚刚对我的未婚夫撒了一个大谎
And I've just told the most terrible one to the man I'm about to marry.
难道你不觉得任何谎言都算背叛吗
Do you feel that any lie is a betrayal?
我说的是乘飞机
I said flying.
谢谢你送我过来
Thanks for bringing me out here.
他喜欢飞机
Well, he likes the planes.
要我给你带点纪念品回来吗
Can I bring something back for you? A souvenir?
他喜欢那种雪花水晶球吗
Does he like those little snow globes?
摇一摇  就会有雪落下来的那种水晶球
You know, you shake them up and then the snow floats down.
当然  我很喜欢  非常感谢你
Sure, I'd really like that. Thank you so much.
他才八岁
He's 8.
他很有两下子
He's good at it.
我读过相关文章
I've read an article about this.
八岁的孩子都招人讨厌
All children are hideous at the age of 8.
-这是很正常的现象  -好吧
- It's quite normal. - Well...
也许等我回来之后
Maybe when I come back,
我们该享受一下二人时光
the two of us ought to spend some time together on our own.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
再见
Bye.
再见  乔纳
Bye, Jonah.
再见
Bye.
乔纳
Jonah.
听着
Listen to me.
你不了解维多利亚
You don't know Victoria.
我都不怎么了解她  她对我来说就是个谜
I hardly know her myself. She's, in fact, a mystery to me.
她经常甩头发  她为什么要这么做
She tosses her hair a lot. Why does she do this?
我不知道  她是抽搐了吗  还是需要剪头发
I have no idea. Is it a twitch? Does she need a haircut?
她能用发卡夹一下头发  别让头发挡着脸吗
Could she use a barrette to keep her hair out of her face?
我很想将这类的事情探究清楚
These are the things I'm willing to get to the bottom of.
所以我才和她约会
That is why I am dating her.
仅此而已
That's all I'm doing.
我不会和她同居  也不会娶她
I'm not living with her. I'm not marrying her.
你能体会到其中的区别吗
Can you appreciate the difference?
单身的人都会这么做
This is what single people do.
他们和别人约会  看对方是否适合自己
They try other people on and see how they fit.
但大家都在彼此适应  人无完人
But everybody's an adjustment. Nobody's perfect.
根本就没有什么完美...
There's no such thing as a perfect...
走吧
Come on.
爸爸  我那天和杰西卡聊到来生
Dad, I was talking to Jessica about reincarnation.
她说你和安妮在前世认识
She says you knew Annie in another life.
-安妮是谁  -给我们写信的人
- Who's Annie? - The one who wrote us.
但杰西卡说  你和安妮前世没能在一起
But Jessica says, you and Annie never got together in that life.
你们的心就好比残缺的拼图
So your hearts are like puzzles with missing pieces.
当你们在一起后  拼图就完整了
And when you get together, the puzzle's complete.
该死
Goddamn it.
我知道这件事  而你不知道的原因
The reason I know this and you don't,
是因为我更年轻  心灵更纯洁
is because I'm younger and purer,
所以我更能接近宇宙的力量
so I'm more in touch with cosmic forces.
这些都是谁告诉你的
Who told you this stuff?
杰西卡
Jessica.
我真心希望你不会和杰西卡结婚
I sincerely hope you're not marrying Jessica.
♪我还记得那些数着日子过的时光♪
♪ I remember the days of just keeping time ♪
♪那时终日慵懒  无所事事♪
♪ of hanging around in sleepy towns forever ♪
♪几英里的小路上空无一人♪
♪ Back roads empty for miles ♪
♪不能让梦想屈服于现实♪
♪ Well, you can't have a dream and cut it to fit ♪
♪但当我看见你时  我就知道♪
♪ But when I saw you, I knew ♪
♪我们天生一对♪
♪ We'd go together ♪
♪犹如眨眼与微笑♪
♪ like a wink and a smile ♪
♪在铁路旁♪
♪ Leave your old jalopy ♪
♪丢掉你的旧车♪
♪ By the railroad track ♪
♪我们去买一辆豪华的♪
♪ We'll get a hip double-dip tip-toppy ♪
♪双座庞蒂亚克♪
♪ Two-seat Pontiac ♪
♪你可以尽情疾驰  不用减速♪
♪ So you can rev her up don't go slow ♪
♪一路绿灯  无拘无束♪
♪ It's only green lights and all rights ♪
♪让我们一同前行  带着狡黠与笑意♪
♪ Let's go together with a wink and a smile ♪
♪给我眨个眼  再微微笑♪
♪ Give me a wink and a smile ♪
♪我们天生一对  犹如眨眼与微笑♪
♪ We go together like a wink and a smile ♪
♪我的心中充满了旋律♪
♪ Now my heart is music ♪
♪多么简单的一首曲子♪
♪ Such a simple song ♪
♪再次唱响  乐章永不停息♪
♪ Sing it again The notes never end ♪
♪这才是我的归属♪
♪ This is where I belong ♪
♪你的声音♪
♪ Just the sound of your voice ♪
♪你眼中的光芒♪
♪ The light in your eyes ♪
♪我们离昨日相距甚远♪
♪ We're so far away from yesterday ♪
♪带着眨眼与微笑  在一起吧♪
♪ Together with a wink and a smile ♪
♪我们天生一对♪
♪ We go together ♪
♪犹如眨眼与微笑♪
♪ like a wink and a smile ♪
我看着他在海滩上和儿子玩耍
I watched him play with his son at the beach.
你去和他说话了吗
Did you talk to him?
我办不到
Couldn't do it.
我怎么会跑来这里啊
How did I get here?
你撒了个谎  然后上了飞机
You told a lie and got on a plane.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I mean.
我明天会再次去那个地方
I'm going back over there tomorrow
然后和他说话  我会的
and talk to him. I am.
-好的  再见  -贝琪
- Okay. Good. Goodbye. - Beck.
怎么了
What?
这样做是不是疯了
Is this crazy?
不是  这点反而是最奇怪的
No, that's the weirdest part about it.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you too.
-晚安  -再见
- Good night. - Bye.
很高兴见到你  格雷格呢
It's so good to see you. Where's Greg?
你好
Hello.
-然后发生了什么  -很显然  我离开了
- So then what happened? - So then I left, obviously.
你当时站在马路中间吗
You were standing in the middle of the street?
你知道那种赤身裸体走在大街上
You know that dream when you're walking down the street naked
然后所有人都看着你的那种梦吧
and everyone is looking at you.
我喜欢那种梦
I love that dream.
和这种羞辱比起来都不算什么  根本不算什么
That was nothing compared to this humiliation. Nothing!
-但他看见你了  对吗  -他看见我了
- But he saw you, right? - He saw me.
-你们当时面对面  -他说了"你好"
- You were face to face. - He said hello.
他说了"你好"  你说了什么
He said hello. And what did you say?
我也只能说"你好"
And all I could say was hello.
天哪
Oh, my God.
-我也只能说"你好"  -这是个预兆
- And all I could say was hello. - It's a sign.
-这代表着我看了太多遍这部电影  -安妮
- It's a sign that I have watched this movie too many times. - Oh, Annie.
太傻了
So stupid!
从我开始听那个破电台节目的那一刻起
From the minute I listened to that stupid programme on the radio,
我就成了一个彻头彻尾的混蛋
I've been a complete jerk.
你不是混蛋
You are not a jerk.
谢谢  我是白痴
Thank you. An idiot!
你不知道她是谁  安妮
You don't know who she was, Annie.
我见过她  我有她的照片
I saw her. I have a picture of her.
我给你看她的照片
I'll show you a picture of her.
那个在西雅图的侦探给我寄了一张她的照片
That detective in Seattle sent me a picture of her.
给  你看  这就是她的模样
Here! See, that's exactly what she looks like.
这不过是某个人的背影
This is a picture of someone's back.
这就是她  而且他非常爱她
Well, it's her and he was crazy about her.
这是什么
What's this?
这封信是从西雅图寄来的
This is from Seattle.
贝琪
Becky.
我把你的信寄出去了
So I mailed your letter.
"亲爱的安妮
"Dear Annie.
感谢你的来信  信写得很好
Thanks for your letter. It was great.
你似乎是个不错的人
You sound neat.
我们很期待能够在情人节当天
We're very excited about meeting you
和你在纽约见面  看看我们是不是
in New York on Valentine's Day and seeing if we are...
天对地双
M-f-e-o.
期待能和你很快见面  西雅图夜未眠先生留"
See you soon. Sleepless in Seattle."
天对地双
M-f-e-o?
天造一对  地设一双
Made for each other.
文风很可爱
It's cute.
就像给你留了一条小线索
It's like a little clue.
所以他文笔不好  多大点事
So he can't write. Big deal.
我们总是过度高估男人的语言能力
Verbal ability is a highly overrated thing in a guy.
正是对这种能力的可悲需求
And our pathetic need for it
才会让我们陷入这么多麻烦
is what gets us into so much trouble.
我要奔回沃尔特的怀抱  前提是他还要我的话
I'm going to run back to Walter's arms, if he'll still have me.
那这封信呢
What about the letter?
这封信没有任何意义  这是在我去之前写的
It's nothing. It was written before I went out there.
在他和那个坏女人好上之前
Before the ho.
唯一的问题是  她看上去不像是坏女人
The only thing is, she didn't look like a ho.
她看上去像是可以和我们做朋友的人
She looked like somebody we would have been friends with.
你在机场见过她  又在这里见到了她
You saw her in the airport and then here?
我想和她说话
And I tried to talk to her.
就好像我认识她一样  感觉很奇怪
It was like I knew her or something. It was weird.
你是指那种似曾相识的感觉吗
You mean like a déjà-vu thing?
非常法式的似曾相识感  明白吗
It was very French déjà-vu-ish kind of thing. Oui?
明白  至少你又开始约会了
Oui. At least you're out there seeing people again.
这很棒
That's terrific.
其实我只和一个人约过会
Well, I mean, there's really just the one.
维多利亚
Victoria.
你不喜欢维多利亚吗
You don't like Victoria?
她的笑声像鬣狗
She laughs like a hyena.
真的吗
Is this true?
不是
No!
有一点像吧  告诉他们你做了什么
Sort of. Yeah, a little bit. But, tell them what you did.
-爸爸  -跟他们说说电台节目的事
- Dad... - Tell them about the radio show.
-说吧  -爸爸
- Go ahead. - Dad...
他们想听  说吧  告诉他们
They wanna hear it. Go ahead. Tell them. Tell them.
平安夜那晚  他给一个电台热线节目打电话
Christmas Eve, he phones in one of those radio call-in shows.
说我需要一个新妻子
And tells them I need a new wife.
开玩笑吧
Oh, you're kidding.
真体贴
That's so sweet.
现在他对一个给我写信的女人着了迷
Now he's obsessed with this one woman who wrote me.
-没开玩笑吧  -真的
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
她想和我在帝国大厦的楼顶见面
She wants to meet me at the top of Empire State Building.
在情人节当天
On Valentine's Day.
-就像那部电影一样  -什么电影
- It's like that movie. - What movie?
《金玉盟》  你们没看过吗
An Affair to Remember. Did you ever see it?
天哪
Oh, God.
加里·格兰特和黛博拉·蔻儿主演
Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr.
是卡尔还是蔻儿
Is that "Karr" Or "Kerr"?
-蔻儿  -卡尔
- Kerr. - Karr.
好吧
Okay.
她本来会在帝国大厦的楼顶和他见面
She's gonna meet him at the top of the Empire State Building.
但她被出租车撞到了
Only she got hit by a taxi.
他一直在等  我记得好像还在下雨
And he waited and waited. And it was raining, I think.
她因为自尊心  不愿意告诉他...
And then she's too proud to tell him that she's...
自己瘸了
crippled.
他也因为自尊心  不愿意去探究她没来的原因
And he's too proud to find out why she doesn't come.
但他最终还是去见她了
But he comes to see her anyway.
我忘了原因  不过
And I forget why, but...
他去见她时的那一幕太感人了
Oh, it's so amazing when he comes to see her.
因为他都没有注意到
Because he doesn't even notice
她没有起身和他打招呼
that she doesn't get up to say hello.
他极尽挖苦与讽刺
And he's very bitter.
你以为他会直接
And you think that he's just gonna
走出那扇门
walk out the door
永远不知道她为什么没来
and never know why.
她就躺在那里
She's just lying there, you know.
躺在沙发上
Like, on the couch with
把一条小毯子盖在她萎缩的双腿上
this little blanket over her shrivelled little legs.
然后
And...
你没事吧
Are you all right?
她没事
She's fine.
突然  他说  "我看到了那幅画"
And suddenly, he goes, "I saw the painting"
然后他走进了卧室
And he, like, goes to the bedroom.
环顾四周  再走出卧室看着她
And he looks, and he comes out and looks at her.
然后他就...
And he kind of just...
他们解开了误会  相拥在一起  太感人了
They know and hug and it's so...
这是女人看的电影
That's a chick's movie.
我也这么想
I would say so.
什么样的人
What kind of a person would
会给电台节目里听到的人写信
write to someone they heard on the radio?
全国上下有成百上千个女人都给我寄了信
I got hundreds of letters from women all over the country.
饥不择食的女人
Desperate women.
那些女人只是想找个好男人
Just because someone is looking for a nice guy,
这并不代表她们就饥不择食
it doesn't make them desperate.
「贪婪而缺爱」  这个说法如何
How about rapacious and love-starved?
不行
No.
被恐怖分子杀死的几率都比在四十岁之后
It's easier to be killed by a terrorist than to find a husband
-找到丈夫的几率大  -根本不是这样
- after the age of 40... - That is absolutely untrue!
好吧  亲爱的  好吧
Right, honey. Right.
我又不是要找一个邮购新娘
Well, I'm not looking for a mail-order bride.
我只想找一个
I just want somebody
能和我在吃晚饭时好好聊天的女人
that I can have a decent conversation with over dinner.
不会因为刚看过的电影
You know, without it falling down
就哭得稀里哗啦的那种女人
into weepy tears over some movie that she just saw.
她太多愁善感了
She's very emotional.
-不过看到《十二金刚》结尾时  我也哭了  -谁不哭呢
- Although, I cried at the end of The Dirty Dozen. - Who didn't?
吉姆·布朗正往那些通风井里面扔手榴弹
Jim Brown was throwing these hand grenades down these air shafts.
然后理查德·杰克尔和李·马文
And Richard Jaeckel and Lee Marvin
坐在装甲运兵车顶上
were sitting on top of this armoured personnel carrier.
他们打扮成纳粹的样子  还有...
They were dressed up like Nazis. And it was...
-秦尼·罗柏斯  -秦尼·罗柏斯
- Trini Lopez... - Trini Lopez...
在他们空降纳粹敌后区的时候
He busted his neck when they were
他被打中了脖子
parachuting down behind the Nazi lines.
别说了
Stop it!
理查德·杰克尔  在电影开始的时候
Richard Jaeckel, at the beginning,
戴着一个亮闪闪的钢盔  因为他是宪兵
he had on a shiny helmet, because he was an MP.
别说了  天哪  我爱那部电影
Please, no more. God, I love that movie.
这是我看过的最好的电影了
This is the best movie I've ever seen in my life.
哪里好了
What's so great about it?
你得找到她  乔纳  你得去见她
You have to find her, Jonah. You have to go to her.
你知道去纽约要花多少钱吗
Do you know how much money it costs to go to New York?
没人知道
Nobody knows.
价格基本每天都在变
It changes practically every day.
你有多少钱
How much money do you have?
80块
80 dollars.
我有42块  应该够乘出租车了
I have 42. That'll probably cover taxi cabs.
但我要怎么过去呢
But how would I get there?
亲爱的  我得去给别人送票
Honey, I have to run these tickets over to someone.
在我回来之前  帮我看一下家好吗
Can you keep an eye on things out front till I get back?
好的  妈妈
Sure, Mum.
鲍德温
93年2月14号
西雅图机场  至  纽约肯尼迪机场
联合航空  班次FL1597
-你要靠窗的座位还是靠过道的座位  -靠窗
- You want a window seat or aisle? - Window.
-你想要水果拼盘吗  -不知道  我会想要吗
- You want a fruit plate? - I don't know. Do I?
我宁死也不要吃飞机上的食物
I'd rather die than eat airplane food.
我会告知航空公司你已满十二岁
I'm telling them you're 12
这样你就可以单独搭乘飞机
so you can fly unaccompanied
那些空姐也不会围着你烦个不停了
and the stewardess won't carry you around and stuff like that.
你疯了吧  谁会相信我满12岁了
Are you crazy? Who'd believe I'm 12?
如果电脑上有记录  他们什么都会信
If it's in the computer, they'll believe anything.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你希望我告知他们
Do you want me to say
和同龄人相比  你身材非常矮小
that you're really, really short for your age,
他们不该对此说什么
and they shouldn't say anything
因为这样会伤害你的感情吗
because it would hurt your feelings?
好  这主意真不错
Yeah. That's a great idea!
♪有时  做女人难♪
♪ Sometimes it's hard to be a woman ♪
♪只为一个男人献上你所有的爱♪
♪ Giving all your love to just one man ♪
沃尔特
Walter.
你要错过那班火车了
You're gonna miss the train.
不  我不会
No, I'm not.
我好高兴  贝琪
I'm so happy, Becky.
我终于高兴了
Finally, I feel happy.
这样才对  这才是我的现实生活
This is right. This is real.
其他事都是因为我看了太多电影
Everything else is what happens when you watch too many movies.
从而完全忽视了真正重要的东西
And you completely lose sight of what counts.
请不要告诉别人发生了什么
Please, don't tell anybody what happened.
如果有人知道我做了什么事
Because I would be so absolutely mortified
哪怕他们只知道一点点
if anyone knew I did anything
我都会羞愧难当
even remotely close to what I have done.
谢谢  谢谢  你保证吗
Thank you, thank you. Do you promise?
我保证
I promise.
西雅图夜未眠先生已成历史
Sleepless in Seattle is history.
♪如果你爱他♪
♪ And if you love him ♪
♪请为他感到自豪♪
♪ Oh, be proud of him ♪
♪毕竟  他只是一个男人♪
♪ Cause after all he's just a man ♪
♪支持你的他♪
♪ Stand by your man ♪
-我只是...  -我只是...
- I was just... - I was just...
-说吧  -不  你先说
- Go ahead. - No, you go.
好吧  我只想说  圣诞节之后
Okay. Well, I was just gonna say that ever since Christmas...
你有点变了  有些心不在焉  和我也有些疏远了
you've been different, kind of distracted, distant.
但现在  我感觉你
But now it feels as if you're coming back from
变回了原来的自己
wherever you were.
是的
I am.
我只是...
I was just...
我只是  我觉得是我紧张了
I just... I just got... I think I got nervous.
但这很正常  对吗
But that's normal, right?
难道你没有为那件事紧张过吗
I mean, don't you ever feel nervous about... you know?
什么事
What?
永恒
Forever.
没有
No.
好吧
Well...
我紧张了
I did.
你知道我是怎么想的吗
And... You know what I think?
我感觉我们太般配了
I think I thought it was too perfect, you know.
我开始怀疑我们会不会
I started to wonder if we were the human equivalent
正正得负
of two rights making a wrong.
你知道那是什么感觉吗
You know what it was?
感觉就像命运  但也不是
It was like kismet, but not,
不知你明不明白我的意思
if you see what I mean.
你必须得长大
You have to grow up.
不能再继续抱有
You just can't keep having
那些青少年般的幻象
all these adolescent fantasies about...
比如自己今后的生活会有多刺激
how exciting life is gonna be.
别怪我  但我喜欢这花色
Don't hate me, but I love this pattern.
-不会吧  -真的
- You couldn't. - I do.
这和我外婆的瓷器一模一样
This is just like my grandmother's china.
你们要几套餐具
How many place settings should I put down.
-十套  -十套
- Ten. - Ten.
没错  八套太少  十二套又...
Exactly. Eight is too few, twelve is...
太多
Too many.
沃尔特
Walter.
这曾是我母亲的戒指
It was my mother's.
我让人把尺寸改小了
I had them size it down.
她的手指很粗
She had really fat fingers.
真好看
It's so beautiful.
如果全世界的戒指
It's exactly what I would pick out if I had
都可供我挑选  我还是会选这一枚
every ring in the whole world to choose from.
你明白我的意思了吗
You see what I mean?
有的人喜欢恋爱中充满惊喜
There are people who would like a relationship to be full of surprises,
但我不是那种人
but I am not one of those people.
我不是
No, siree.
人们过分看重了惊喜
Surprises are highly overrated.
我明天一早就走
I'm leaving first thing in the morning,
但我只会去一个晚上
but I'm only gonna be gone one night.
克拉丽丝会来
Clarise is gonna be here.
你们可以一起看很多
So you'll be able to see plenty of
《格尔拉多》和《猛鬼街》  我不会知道的
Geraldo and Nightmare on Elm Street 12. I will never know.
你要和她一起去吗
Are you going with her?
我要和维多利亚一起去  没错
I'm going with Victoria, yes.
别想耍花招  明白吗
Don't try anything tricky. Understand?
别等我一出门就去毒藤丛里打滚
Don't go rolling in poison ivy as soon as I leave the house.
也不要把自己锁在柜子里
Or lock yourself in the closet
或者让自己受伤
or do anything that makes you need stitches.
如果你的手指断了  就会一直断着
If your finger falls off, it's staying off.
没人会帮你把断指冰敷  然后送你去医院
No one's gonna pack it on ice and take you to hospital,
好让你成为激光手术的医学奇迹
so that you can be a breakthrough in laser surgery.
是因为巴尔的摩的那个女人吗
Is this about that woman in Baltimore?
她叫安妮
Annie.
-我才不在乎你会干什么  -很好
- I don't care what you do! - Good! Fine!
告诉你我这周末会干什么
I'll tell you what I'm doing this weekend.
我要享受性生活
I'm getting laid.
进入90年代  却没人有性生活了
1990s and nobody's getting laid.
我是全美国这周末唯一有性生活的男人
I'm the only man in the America who's getting laid this weekend.
我的性生活经历可不多
And I haven't been laid that much.
大学里有过六个女孩  也许是七个
Six girls in college. Maybe seven.
你站在那里多久了
How long have you been there?
一直站着呢
Forever.
你听到我说什么了
What did you hear me just say?
"大学里有过六个女孩  也许是七个"
"Six girls in college. Maybe seven."
七个  八个  还有玛丽·凯利
Seven. Eight! Mary Kelly.
我就喜欢她
This is the one I like.
乔纳  事实上  你不会喜欢上任何女人
Jonah, the fact is, you're not gonna like any woman,
因为她们不是你妈妈
because it isn't your mother.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
-安妮哪里不好了  -乔纳  闭嘴
- What's wrong with Annie? - Oh, Jonah, shut up!
闭嘴  闭嘴  妈妈从来没对我说过闭嘴
Shut up? Shut up? Mum never said shut up to me.
妈妈从来不对我大吼大叫
Mum never yelled at me.
-谈话到此结束  -我们为什么不能去纽约
- This conversation is finished. - Why can't we go to New York?
我们不可能乘上飞机
There is no way that we are going on a plane
去见一个可能是疯子的女人
to meet some woman who could be a crazy, sick lunatic.
难道你没看过《致命诱惑》吗
Didn't you see Fatal Attraction?
你不让我看
You wouldn't let me.
我看过  那电影把我吓死了
Well, I saw it! And it scared the shit out of me.
把全美国所有的男人都吓死了
It scared the shit out of every man in America!
你不同意  我就不走
I'm not leaving till you say yes.
我恨你  我恨你  我恨你
I hate you! I hate you! I hate you!
很好  你可以好好和奥普拉说说[著名脱口秀主持人]That's good! You'll have a lot to tell Oprah
你爸爸是怎么毁了你的一生
how your dad destroyed your life
就因为他要享受一个特别的周末
because he had to go off for a weekend special
去假日旅馆享受
at the Holiday Inn!
乔纳  克拉丽丝来了  我得走了
Jonah, Clarise is here and I've got to go.
乔纳
Hey, Jonah.
Jonah?
好吧  乔纳  听着  我得走了
All right. Jonah, listen, I've got to go.
乔纳
Jonah.
Hey, Jonah.
乔纳
Jonah!
Jonah.
乔纳
杰西卡  亲爱的  你得告诉我们他在哪
Jessica, honey. You have tell us where he is.
乔纳的爸爸很着急
Jonah's daddy is very upset.
杰西卡  我是你爸爸
Jessica, this is your father.
赶紧告诉我们他在哪
Tell us where he is. Right this minute!
-NY  -什么意思
- NY - What is that?
"没门"
"No way."
"没门"的缩写是MM
That's N-W!
纽约  他已经在去纽约的路上了
New York. He's on his way to New York.
-什么  -怎么去的
- What? - How?
-联合航空597号航班  -杰西卡
- United, 597. - Jessica.
-什么时候起飞  -7点半
- When does it leave? - Seven thirty.
给  送你一个别针
Here you go. Here's a nice pin for you
-感谢搭乘我们的航班  -谢谢
- for flying with us. - Thank you.
-不客气  需要我帮你拿包吗  -不用
- You're welcome. Can I take this for you? - No.
-孩子  去哪  -帝国大厦
- Where to, kid? - Empire State Building.
等等
Hold on.
帝国大厦
Empire State Building.
下次别站得离路边这么近
Get a little further away from the curb next time, mac.
去吧
Come on.
到了
There it is.
你要上去干什么  从楼顶往下吐口水吗
What are you going to do up there? Spit off the top?
不
No,
我要去见我的新妈妈
I'm going to meet my new mother.
前往观景台
帝国大厦
打扰了  我是乔纳  你是安妮吗
Excuse me. I'm Jonah. Are you Annie?
不  我是辛西娅
No, I'm Cynthia.
打扰了  你是安妮吗
Excuse me, are you Annie?
桌子的位置很不错  谢谢
Great table. Thanks.
有什么问题吗
Is something wrong?
要来点喝的吗
Can I get you a drink?
要香槟吗
Some champagne?
好的  好的
Fine. Fine.
能给我们上一瓶多姆·德路易斯[演员]吗
Can we have a bottle of Dom DeLuise.
-开玩笑的  -这是个笑话
- Just kidding. - It was a joke.
-他指的是唐培里侬香槟王  -知道了
- He meant Dom Perignon. - I got it.
景色真美  不是吗
Beautiful view, isn't it.
沃尔特
Walter...
有些话我必须告诉你
There's something I have to tell you.
抱歉  我有急事
Hey! Sorry, I have an emergency.
钱  钱  钱  看到了吗
Money, money, money, see?
所以他现在可能在帝国大厦楼顶
So he could be on top of the Empire State Building now?
不
No.
我想可能会吧
I guess he could be.
不
No.
和他无关  沃尔特  是我的原因
It's not him, Walter. It's me.
我做不到
I can't do this.
安妮  我爱你
Look, Annie, I love you.
但先别扯这个吧
But let's leave that out of this.
我不希望成为你将就的对象
I don't want to be someone that you're settling for.
我不希望成为任何人将就的对象
I don't want to be someone that anyone settles for.
婚姻本身就已经足够艰难
Marriage is hard enough
更不用说在期望如此之低的情况下
without bringing such low expectations into it.
不是吗
Isn't it?
沃尔特  我配不上你
Walter, I don't deserve you.
不  我觉得这么说不合适
No, I wouldn't put it that way.
不过  我接受
But...okay.
你没事吗
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
-怎么了  -看
- What? - Look.
这是个预兆
It's a sign.
谁需要预兆
Who needed a sign?
沃尔特
Walter,
我得走了
I have to go.
乔纳
Jonah!
-爸  爸  -乔纳
- Dad! Dad! - Jonah?
如果你出事了怎么办
What if something happened to you?
如果我找不到你怎么办
What if I couldn't get to you?
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
那我该怎么办
What would I have done?
你是我的家人  是我的一切
You are my family. You're all I've got.
我以为她会在这  我以为她会来
I thought she'd be here. I thought she'd come.
我们过得挺好的  不是吗  我们挺好的吧
We're doing okay, aren't we? I mean, are we okay?
我们不是过得挺好的吗
Aren't we all right?
到目前为止  我做过蠢事吗
So far, have I done anything really stupid?
没有
No.
我有没有毁了我们的生活
Have I screwed it up for the both of us?
没有
No.
帝国大厦
-能去观景台吗  -抱歉  女士  已经太晚了
- Observation deck? - Sorry, ma'am, but it's too late.
不  求求你  我真的得上去
No, please. I really need to get up there.
我们要关门了  今晚不搭客了
We're closing up. No more runs tonight.
听我说
Listen...
我能去看一眼吗  我本该和一个人在上面见面
Can I just take a look? There's someone I was supposed to meet.
他很可能不在
He's probably not there,
但我要是不看一眼  我永远都不会甘心
but if I don't at least look, I'll always wonder about it.
加里·格兰特  对吗
Cary Grant, right?
你知道那部电影
You know that movie?
我妻子的最爱之一
It's one of my wife's favourites.
也许等我们回家之后  我们可以养条狗
Maybe when we get home, we'll get a dog.
好吧
Okay.
"好吧"是什么意思
What do you mean, okay?
你不想养狗吗
Wouldn't you like to have a dog?
当然想
Sure.
抱歉  女士  空无一人
I'm sorry, ma'am. Empty.
能让我待一会吗
Can I take a minute?
去吧
Go ahead.
我把包落在望远镜旁了
I left it by the telescopes.
-是你  -是我
- It's you. - It's me.
我在马路上见过你
I saw you in the street.
你是安妮吗
Are you Annie?
没错
Yes.
你就是安妮
You're Annie?
这肯定是你的熊
This must be yours.
我是乔纳
I'm Jonah.
这是我爸爸  他叫萨姆
This is my dad. His name is Sam.
你好  乔纳
Hi, Jonah.
萨姆
Sam.
-它叫什么  -霍华德
- And who's this? - Howard.
霍华德
Oh, Howard.
你好  霍华德
Hello, Howard.
我们该走了
We'd better go.
好吗
Shall we?
♪让某个人幸福  这很重要♪
♪ It's so important to make someone happy ♪
♪让那个人幸福♪
♪ Make just one someone happy ♪
♪让你和她心心相印♪
♪ Make just one heart to heart you ♪
萨姆
Sam,
很高兴认识你
it's nice to meet you.
♪见到你时  只有那张脸庞因你而点亮♪
♪ One face that lights when it nears you ♪
♪对那个女孩来说  你就是一切♪
♪ One girl you're, you're everything to ♪
♪当你赢得  它即衰竭♪
♪ Fail if you win it ♪
♪来去只在一瞬之间♪
♪ Comes and goes in a minute ♪
♪ 生活中真正可以依赖的东西是什么♪
♪ Where's the real stuff in life to cling to ♪
♪答案就是爱♪
♪ Love is the answer ♪
♪答案就是  一个爱人♪
♪ Someone to love is the answer ♪
♪一旦你找到她♪
♪ Once you've found her ♪
♪围绕她建立你的小世界♪
♪ Build your world around her ♪
♪让某个人幸福♪
♪ Make someone happy ♪
♪让那个人幸福♪
♪ Make just one someone happy ♪
♪那么你也会感到幸福♪
♪ And you will be happy too ♪
♪当我坠入爱河♪
♪ When I fall in love ♪
♪那必将是永恒♪
♪ It will be forever ♪
♪否则我永远不碰爱情♪
♪ Or I'll never fall in love ♪
♪在一个浮躁的世界  我永远不碰爱情♪
♪ I'll never, never fall in love in a restless world ♪
♪如同现在这样的世界♪
♪ Like this is ♪
♪爱情尚未开始就结束了♪
♪ Love is ended before it's begun ♪
♪太多月光下的吻♪
♪ And too many moonlight kisses ♪
♪在日光之下  就会冷却♪
♪ Seem to cool in the warmth of the sun ♪
♪当我交出我的心♪
♪ When I give my heart ♪
♪那必将是彻底交出♪
♪ It will be completely ♪
♪否则我将永远不交出我的心♪
♪ Or I'll never give my heart ♪
♪当我可以感受到♪
♪ And the moment I can feel ♪
♪你也是同样的想法♪
♪ That you feel that way too ♪
♪就是我坠入爱河的时候♪
♪ Is when I fall in love ♪
♪当我坠入爱河♪
♪ When I fall in love ♪
♪当我爱上你♪
♪ When I fall in love with you ♪
♪给我个吻  让我魂牵梦绕♪
♪ Give me a kiss to build a dream on and my imagination ♪
♪那个吻将让我欢欣鼓舞♪
♪ Will thrive upon that kiss ♪
♪亲爱的  我的要求仅限于此♪
♪ Sweetheart I ask no more than this, ♪
♪一个让我可以魂牵梦绕的吻♪
♪ A kiss to build a dream on ♪
♪在离开我之前  给我一个吻吧♪
♪ Give me a kiss before you leave me ♪
♪魂牵梦绕  将慰藉我心♪
♪ And my imagination will feed my hungry heart ♪
♪在我们分别前  给我留点念想♪
♪ Leave me one thing before we part ♪
♪一个让我可以魂牵梦绕的吻♪
♪ A kiss to build a dream on ♪